[轻柔的管弦乐演奏]
[GENTLE ORCHESTRAL MUSIC PLAYING]
大卫·马兰：好了 这是CS50的S介绍
DAVID MALAN: All right, this is CS50's Introduction
到使用Python语言编程
to Programming with Python.
我的名字是David Malan 这是我们关于函数和变量的一周
My name is David Malan and this is our week on functions and variables.
但很有可能的是 你们中的许多人 大多数人 以前从未真正编程过
But odds are, many of you, most of you, have never actually programmed before.
因此 让我们从这样做开始吧
So let's start by doing just that.
让我在这里继续 打开我的计算机
Let me go ahead here and open up my computer
在它上面 有一个名为Visual Studio Code或VS的程序
and on it, a program called Visual Studio Code or VS
代码 这是一个非常流行的程序
Code, which is just a very popular program nowadays
用于实际编写代码
for actually writing code.
现在 您不必使用此特定工具编写代码
Now, you don't have to write code using this particular tool.
事实上 我们一天结束时所需要的
In fact, all we need at the end of the day
是一种所谓的文本编辑器 一种编写文本的程序
is a so-called text editor, a program for writing text.
见鬼 如果你真的想 你甚至可以用
And, heck, if you really want, you could even use something
比如Google Docs或Microsoft Word
like Google Docs or Microsoft Word.
你必须以正确的格式保存它
You'd have to save it in the right format,
但说到底 你所需要的只是一个写文本的程序
but really, at the end of the day, all you need is a program for writing text
因为这就是代码--文本
because that's what code is-- text.
现在 在这个特别的项目中 我将
Now within this particular program, I'm going
能够创建一个或多个文件
to have the ability to create one or more files
通过屏幕的这个顶部
via this top portion of the screen.
我要做的就是潜入
And I'm going to do so by diving right in
在我的屏幕底部做这件事
and doing this at the bottom of my screen.
在我的屏幕底部是一个所谓的终端窗口
At the bottom of my screen is a so-called terminal window
这是底层的命令行界面或CLI界面
and this is a command line interface or CLI interface to the underlying
电脑 无论是你的Mac还是你的PC 甚至是云中的某个服务器
computer, be it your Mac or your PC or even some server in the cloud.
我在这里要做的就是直接写“代码” 然后
And what I'm going to do here is literally write, "code" and then
我要编码的文件的名称 例如 Hello.py
the name of the file that I want to code, for instance, Hello.py.
我们很快就会看到 您用Python编写的任何程序通常都有一个文件
As we'll soon see, any program that you write in Python generally has a file
以.py结尾的名称 向计算机表明它确实是一个程序
name that ends in .py to indicate to the computer that it's indeed a program
用Python语言编写的
written in Python.
现在你会看到在我屏幕的顶部 我有一个闪烁的光标
Now you'll see here at the top of my screen, I have a blinking cursor,
第一行--这是我的代码的第一行--
a line one-- which is where the very first line of my code is going to go--
然后是一个选项卡 它让我想起这个文件的名称Hello.py
and then just a tab that reminds me of the name of this file Hello.py.
虽然我对Python了解不多
And without even knowing much Python, I'm
我的第一个程序如下
going to write my very first program here as follows--
print（“hello world”）
print("hello,world").
你会看到 在我的键盘上 我的一些想法
And you'll see that, at my keyboard, some of my thoughts
对我来说已经结束了
were finished for me.
我只需要输入一个括号 另一个就会自动出现
I only had to type one parenthesis and the other one automatically appeared,
这就是我们在这里看到的工具的特点
and that's just the feature that we'll see of tools like this tool here.
即使你以前从未编程过
Now even if you've never programmed before,
你可以猜测 推断出这个简单的程序要做什么
odds are you can guess, infer what this simple program is going to do.
只有一句台词 print（“hello world”）
And it's only one line. print("hello,world").
实际上 当我最终运行这个程序时
Indeed, when I run this program ultimately,
它只会说 你好 世界
it's just going to say, Hello to the world.
事实上 这是一个非常著名的--
And, in fact, this is a very famous--
也许是最规范的程序
perhaps the most canonical-- program that you
可以用Python或任何其他语言编写你的第一个程序
can write as your very first program in Python or any other language,
这就是我在这里所做的
and so that's what I've done here.
但在我的Mac电脑 我的PC 甚至我的手机上 我通常习惯
But on my Mac, my PC, even my phone, I'm generally in the habit,
就像你一样 双击图标就能运行程序
like you, of running programs by double clicking an icon
或者只是点击屏幕
or just tapping on the screen.
但我在这里没有看到这样的图标
But I see no such icons here.
事实上 这是因为我现在的Mac电脑的界面
And in fact, that's because my interface to at least my current Mac
或PC或云中的某个服务器 也只是一个CLI--
or PC or some server in the cloud, is again only a CLI--
命令行接口--尽管它
command line interface-- which even though it
我可能会觉得这是从菜单、按钮和图标中后退一步
might feel like it's a step back from the menus and buttons and icons
你和我每天都认为是理所当然的 你会发现 我们认为
that you and I take for granted every day, you'll find, we think,
它最终会是一个更强大的界面
that it's ultimately a much more powerful interface and incredibly
在现实世界中的程序员中很流行
popular to use among programmers in the real world.
所以要运行这个程序 我必须使用一个命令
So to run this program, I'm going to have to use a command
我将把光标移回屏幕底部
and I'm going to move my cursor back down to the bottom of the screen
这里我之前已经运行了一个命令--
here where previously I already ran one command--
在我的计算机中具有打开VS Code效果的命令Code
the command Code which has the effect of opening VS Code in my computer,
然后我传入了我想编码的文件名
and then I passed in the name of the file that I wanted to code up.
现在我有机会输入第二个命令
Now I have a chance to type a second command,
你会看到第二个美元符号
and you'll see I see a second dollar sign.
这里的美元符号并不表示任何一种货币或货币
Now the dollar sign here doesn't indicate any kind of currency or money,
这只是一个普遍使用的符号
it just is the symbol that's generally used
以指示您的提示符--命令行界面需要的位置
to indicate your prompt-- where the command line interface wants
你需要把这些命令
you to put those commands.
现在我可以在这里运行的命令是这样的--
Now the command I can run here is going to be this--
我将运行Hello.py的Python
I'm going to run Python of Hello.py.
这是为什么呢？
Now why is that?
事实证明 当我用像Python语言这样的语言编写代码时
Well, it turns out that when I actually write code in a language like Python,
它当然存储在那个文件中--
it's of course stored in that file--
您好 但是我需要从上到下解释代码
Hello.py, but I need to interpret the code top to bottom,
从左到右 这样计算机就知道该怎么做了
left to right so that the computer knows what to do.
事实上 在一天结束的时候 即使你不是真的
Indeed, at the end of the day, even if you don't really
对计算机了解很多 你可能已经
know much about computers, you've probably
听说计算机只懂0和1 也就是所谓的二进制
heard the computers only understand zeros and ones, the so-called binary
系统
system.
如果是这样的话 写着“打印”和圆括号的东西
Well if that's the case, then something that says "print" and parentheses
引用引述的Hello world 不一定是0和1
and quote unquote hello world, is not surely zeros and ones.
我们必须以某种方式将其转化为0和1
We have to somehow translate it into the zeros and ones
计算机能理解的信息
that the computer understands.
现在幸运的是 只要你提前安装了这样的程序
Now fortunately, so long as you've installed such a program in advance,
有一个程序和一种叫做Python的语言
there's a program as well as a language called Python.
因此 Python不仅是我们要用来编写代码的语言
So Python is not only a language in which we're going to write code,
它也是一个程序 也就是众所周知的解释器
it's also a program otherwise known as an interpreter
您可以在自己的Mac或PC或云中的某个服务器上免费安装
that you install for free on your own Mac or PC or some server in the cloud
然后您可以运行该程序、该解释器 并将其作为输入传递给它
and you can then run that program, that interpreter, passing to it as input
您的文件的名称与我的类似 Hello.py
the name of your file like mine here, Hello.py.
然后那个程序 那个解释器 就会
And then that program, that interpreter, will
掌握从上到下、从左到右阅读它的过程
handle the process of reading it top to bottom, left to right
并有效地将其转换为那些0和1
and translating it effectively into those zeros and ones
计算机可以理解的
that the computer can understand.
所以我们就这么做吧
So let's do just that.
让我回到这里的VS代码
Let me go back to VS Code here.
我已经输入了Hello.py的Python 但没有按回车键
I already typed out Python of Hello.py but I didn't get hit Enter.
这就是现在要开始的命令
And that's what's now going to kick off this command
希望 如果我没有搞砸这一切
and hopefully, if I didn't mess any of this up,
I should see my very first program's output to the screen.
And voila, hello, world.
So if you too have typed exactly that same code
and have executed exactly that same command,
you will have written your very first program in this case in Python.
Well now let's take a step back and consider,
what is it that we actually just did and what
is it we're looking here on the screen?
Well first and foremost, in most any programming language,
you tend to have access to what are called functions.
A function is like an action or a verb that
lets you do something in the program.
And generally speaking, any language comes with some predetermined set
of functions-- some very basic actions or verbs that the computer will already
know how to do for you, that the language, really,
will know how to do for you.
And you, the programmer, the human, can use those functions at will
to get the computer to do those things.
Now the program in question here, Hello.py is using one function.
And you could perhaps guess what it is.
That function is, of course, going to be this function print
and that print function, of course, doesn't
print some preordained string of text.
That is to say, it prints whatever it is you want it to print.
And here too, do we have another piece of terminology in the world
of programming, namely arguments.
An argument is an input to a function that somehow influences its behavior.
The people who invented Python, of course,
didn't necessarily know what it is you and I
are going to want to print to the screen, so they designed this print
function using these parentheses with the ability
to take as input some string of text, be it
in English or any other human language, that is
what you want this function ultimately to print onto the screen.
那么这个节目最终会在屏幕上做什么呢？
And what is it that the program is ultimately doing on the screen?
嗯 当然是印刷品
Well, it's printing, of course.
它在屏幕上向我们展示了你好 世界
It's showing us hello, world on the screen.
这在编程中通常被称为副作用
And that's generally in programming known as a side effect.
它可以是可视的 也可以是音频的
It can be visual, it can be audio.
在这种情况下 它是出现在屏幕上的东西
In this case, it's something that appears on the screen
因此 功能确实会产生这些副作用
and functions, therefore, can indeed have these side effects.
作为这个动词或动作 他们可以做的一件事是
One of the things they can do as this verb or action is
作为一个副作用显示在屏幕上 就像那些话
to display on the screen as a side effect, something like those words
我们想要的--
that we wanted--
你好 世界
hello, world.
这是我的第一个项目 你知道 我感觉很好
So that's my first program and, you know, I'm feeling pretty good.
一切都按计划进行
Everything worked as planned.
我没有犯任何错误 但是 说实话
I didn't make any mistakes, but, honestly,
当你在学习如何编程 甚至
when you're learning how to program and even
几年后 一旦你学会了如何编程 你就会犯错
once you've learned how to program years later, you're going to make mistakes.
当然 这些错误是指
And those mistakes, of course, are referred
一个你可能已经知道的术语 那就是臭虫
to a term you might already know, which is that of a bug.
Bug是程序中的错误 它们可以采取多种形式
A bug is a mistake in a program and they can take so many forms.
或许 让人欣慰的是 在接下来的几周里
And take comfort, perhaps, in knowing that over the coming weeks,
你会犯很多错误的
you're going to make so many mistakes.
你的代码中会有很多错误 就像我一样
You're going to have so many bugs in your code, just like I did
就像我现在还在做的那样
and just as I still do.
而这些错误本身就是错误
And those bugs themselves are just mistakes
这些都是你要解决的问题
that are problems for you to solve.
在接下来的几周里 我们将为您提供
And over the weeks to come, we're going to give you
许多工具 包括智力和技术 你可以通过这些工具来解决这些问题
a lot of tools both mental and technical via which you can solve those problems.
但在第一次编写程序时 请不要气馁
But just don't get discouraged if when writing your program for the first time
它甚至不是第一次起作用 随着时间的推移 通过练习 它会起作用的
it doesn't even work that first time, it will with time, with practice,
而且有经验
and with experience.
所以现在让我故意犯一个错误
So let me deliberately now make a mistake
有一个非零的机会 我可能已经意外地做了
that there was a non-zero chance I might have done accidentally already,
但我很幸运
but I got lucky.
让我继续说下去 假设我忘了
Let me go ahead and just suppose I forgot
包括诸如右括号之类的内容
to include something like the closing parenthesis
在此行代码的末尾
at the end of this line of code.
代码几乎是正确的 大概有99%是正确的
The code is almost correct, it's like 99% of the way there,
但现在我已经指出了这一点 很明显
but now that I've pointed it out, it's pretty obvious
它漏掉了那个右括号
that it's missing that closed parenthesis.
但即使是那些看似微不足道的小细节 你和我作为人类
But even little, seemingly minor details like that, that you and I as humans
不会真的在乎
wouldn't really care about.
如果你正在发送一封电子邮件或一条短信 不管是什么 那只是一个打字错误
And if you're sending an email or a text message, whatever, it's just a typo.
这没什么大不了的
It's not that big a deal.
这对计算机来说将是一件大事
It is going to be a big deal to the computer.
一台计算机将会把你从字面上理解
A computer is going to take you literally,
如果你没有以语言所期望的方式结束你的思想
and if you don't finish your thought in the way the language expects,
它根本不一定会运行
it's not going to necessarily run at all.
那就让我们开始吧
So let's do this.
我将在这里继续 并清除底部的屏幕
I'm going to go ahead here and clear my screen down at the bottom
这样我就可以重新开始了 我要继续前行
just so I can start fresh, and I'm going to go ahead and run
我的程序的这个版本在进行了更改后删除了
this version of my program after having made that change by deleting
插入语
the parenthesis.
我将继续在Hello.py中再次输入Python 这一次
I'm going to go ahead and type Python again of Hello.py and this time
当我按回车键时 我希望我能看到你好 世界
when I hit Enter, I'm hoping I'm going to see hello, world,
但这里我们在屏幕上有一个错误 即所谓的语法
but here we have an error on the screen, a so-called syntax
错误 指的是我在键盘上犯了一个错误
error, which refers to my having made a mistake at my keyboard.
幸运的是 这一点非常简单
And this one, fortunately, is pretty straightforward.
它确实说过这个左括号从来没有结束过
It indeed says that this open parenthesis was never closed.
因此 这可能是相当直观的
And so that's probably pretty intuitive.
现在我需要做的是 当然 我需要关闭它
Now what I need to do, I need to, of course, to close it.
不幸的是 有时我们会在接下来的几周里看到错误消息
Unfortunately, sometimes the error messages we'll see in the coming weeks
将不会是那么用户友好的
are not going to be nearly that user-friendly.
但是 再一次 有经验 有实践 你会吗？
But there too again, with experience, with practice, will you
在调试这类程序方面做得更好
get better at debugging such programs.
现在让我确保我确实正确地修复了它
Let me now make sure that I indeed fixed it correctly.
现在让我继续运行Hello.py并按Enter键 瞧
Let me go ahead and run now Hello.py and hit Enter and, voila,
我们又开始做生意了
we're back in business.
好吧 让我在这里暂停一下 看看我们现在是否有什么问题
Well let me pause here and see if we have any questions now
关于Python本身、编写或运行这些最简单的程序
about Python itself, writing, or running even the simplest of these programs.
观众：我可以在Word或Microsoft Excel中编写代码吗？
AUDIENCE: Could I write code inside a word or, for example, Microsoft Excel?
要做到这一点 障碍是什么？
And what's the barrier to doing that?
大卫·马兰：一个非常好的问题 请允许
DAVID MALAN: A really good question, and allow
我要非常明确地对整个互联网说
me to very explicitly say to the entire internet
不应使用Microsoft Word编写代码
that you should not write code with Microsoft Word.
我提到这一点只是因为它是一种工具 通过它
I mentioned that only because it's a tool via which
你可以写文本 而代码最终只是文本
you can write text and code is, at the end of the day, just text.
但它不是适合这项工作的工具
But it's not the right tool for the job.
我们不需要粗体、下划线、段落之类的东西
We don't need bold facing, underlining, paragraphs and the like.
我们通常想要比Microsoft Word或Google Docs简单得多的东西
We generally want something much simpler than Microsoft Word or Google Docs.
因此 VS Code只是一个更通用的文本编辑器的例子
And so VS Code is an example of just a more general purpose text editor.
它在生活中的目的是让你这个人类编辑文本
Its purpose in life is to allow you, the human, to edit text.
如今 这些文本编辑器提供了更多的功能
Nowadays these text editors come with many more features.
事实上 您会注意到 即使在我这里的代码中
In fact, you'll notice that even in my code here,
虽然只有一行字 但还是有一点色彩的
even though it's just one line, there's a bit of color to it.
对我来说 “打印”这个词是用蓝色显示的
The word "print" for me is appearing in blue.
括号是黑色的
The parentheses are black.
我们将看到 随着我们编写更多的代码行 越来越多的行
And we'll see as we write more lines of code, more and more of the lines
将以不同的颜色呈现出来
will come to life in various colors.
这只是文本编辑器的一个功能
Now that's just one feature of a text editor.
我们还将看到它具有像这个内置的终端窗口这样的功能
We'll see too that it has features like this built-in terminal window.
它将有一个内置的工具来调试或发现问题
It's going to have a built-in tool for debugging or finding problems
带着密码
with code.
而且它现在是一个非常流行的工具
And it's just a very popular tool nowadays,
但还有很多其他人在那里
but there are many, many others out there.
欢迎您在本课程及以后的课程中使用它们
You're welcome to use them for this course and beyond.
我们碰巧在很大程度上用到了这个
We just happen to use this one in large part
这也是因为你现在也可以在云中免费使用VS Code
too because you can also use VS Code nowadays for free in the cloud.
下面是关于使用Python编程的另一个问题
How about one other question here on programming with Python
或者 你好 更广泛地说 是世界还是语法？
or hello, world or syntax more generally?
观众：是啊 我是想问是不是
AUDIENCE: Yeah I was trying to ask if it's not
可以使用终端窗口运行计算机吗？
possible to run the computer using the terminal window?
大卫·马兰：我想我听到了 是不是--
DAVID MALAN: I think I heard is it not--
是否可以在没有终端窗口的情况下运行该程序？
if it's possible to run the program without the terminal window?
你是不是
Are you--
观众：是的 先生
AUDIENCE: Yes, sir.
大卫·马兰：好吧 你又为我僵住了
DAVID MALAN: OK, you froze for me again.
但让我来推断一下问题是什么
But let me infer what the question is.
所以在这个环境中 当我配置我的计算机时
So in this environment, as I've configured my computer,
我只能通过终端窗口运行这些Python程序
I can only run these Python programs via the terminal window.
这对我 程序员 或者
Now that's good for me, the programmer, or the person who's
我想学习编程 但并不是很好
trying to learn how to program, but it's not very good
如果你想发布这个软件并让其他人使用你的实际代码
if you want to ship this software and have other people use your actual code.
你完全可以编写程序 然后让其他人使用
You can absolutely write programs and then allow other people to use,
不是命令行界面 而是图形用户界面或GUI--
not a command line interface, but a graphical user interface or GUI--
GU I这只是一种机制 我认为
G-U-I. This is just one mechanism and perhaps, I think,
最好的开始写代码的方法
the best one with which to start writing code
因为最终它会给我们更多的控制权
because eventually it's going to give us a lot more control.
请允许我在这里继续前进 但请感受到
Allow me to forge ahead here, but please feel
自由地继续提问 如果只是通过聊天的方式
free to continue asking questions along the way if only via the chat.
现在让我们考虑一下如何改进这个程序
Let's consider now how we might go about improving this program.
让我们来改进这个程序 使它更具互动性
Let's go about improving this program to make it a little more interactive
而不是假设每个人都想被欢迎
and not just assume that everyone is going to want to be greeted
更通用的名称是hello world
more generically as hello, world.
让我们看看我能不能让这个程序说一些像你好 大卫
Let's see if I can't get this program to say something like Hello, David
或者你好 耶利米或者你好 霍雷肖或者其他用户的名字
or Hello, Jeremiah or Hello, Horatio or whatever the actual user's name is.
为了做到这一点 我将回到你好 pi
Well to do this I'm going to go back up to Hello to pi
我会在最上面再加一行代码
and I'm going to add another line of code at the very top that simply says,
比如 你叫什么名字 在末尾多加一个空格
for instance, what's your name, quote unquote with an extra space at the end.
所以我打印给用户一个问题
So I'm printing to the user asking them a question for some input,
但现在我需要另一个函数来获取用户的输入
but now I need another function to actually get input from the user.
而且 完美的是 足够的Python带有一个名为input的函数
And, perfectly, enough Python comes with a function named input.
所以这里我要继续调用一个函数input open paren
So here I'm going to go ahead and call a function input, open paren,
近亲
close paren.
这将提示用户 只是一个闪烁的光标等待
And that's going to prompt the user with just a blinking cursor waiting
让他们输入一些东西
for them to type something in.
如果我读了输入函数的文档
Now it turns out, if I read the documentation for the input function,
它本身也需要一个参数
it actually takes an argument itself.
我不需要单独使用“print” 然后提示用户输入
I don't need to use "print" separately and then prompt the user for input.
所以我可以在我们使用它之前简化这个代码
So I can actually simplify this code before we even use it.
我要继续从print中取出相同的字符串
I'm going to go ahead here and take that same string from print,
把它作为输入函数的参数
put it as an argument to the input function,
彻底摆脱“印刷”
and get rid of the "print" altogether.
而且 事实上 这个“打印”无论如何都会添加一个新的行
And, in fact, that "print" would have added a new line anyway.
现在我得到了一个提示 用户的光标在哪里
So now I've just got a prompt where the user's cursor is
最后会在队伍的最后眨眨眼问他们 你叫什么名字？
going to end up blinking at the end of the line asking them, what's your name?
在我的终端窗口中 我将运行Hello.py的Python 回车
In my terminal window I'm going to run Python of Hello.py, Enter.
好的.
OK.
我们有进展了
We're making progress.
看来这个新的功能输入确实在促使我这个人类
It seems that this new function input is indeed prompting me, the human,
for input输入.
for input.
所以我要输入我的名字
So I'm going to type in my name--
大卫--按回车键
David-- and hit Enter.
不幸的是 这和我的名字没什么关系
Unfortunately, it doesn't really do anything with my name,
它会立即输出
it just outputs it immediately.
好吧 好吧 我可以解决的 对吧？
All right, well, I could fix this, right?
我可以在第二行把“world”改成“David”
I could go up to line 2 and I could change "world" to "David,"
然后回到我的终端窗口 我可以在Hello.py上输入Python 回车
and then back in my terminal window here I can do Python of Hello.py, Enter.
你叫什麽名字？
What's your name?
大卫 进来
David, Enter.
好了
And there we go.
好了 现在我开始行动了
All right now I'm up and running.
现在我的程序正在按预期工作
Now my program is working as intended.
当然 这并不是真正的工作 因为预期在这里
Of course, this isn't really working as intended here.
让我继续假装是我的同事卡特
Let me go ahead and try pretending to be my colleague, Carter here.
卡特的名字是这个
Well Carter's name is this.
我会按回车键 然后我会看到 你好 卡特--
I'm going to go ahead and hit Enter and I'll see, of course, Hello, Carter--
显然不是 因为我硬编码了 可以这么说
well, obviously not, because I've hardcoded, so to speak,
我已经把我的名字写在字符串里了
I've written literally my name inside of the string.
所以我们现在需要一些方法来获取用户的输入
So we need some way now of actually getting back what the user's input is
并最终用它做些什么
and doing something with it ultimately.
为此 我们将利用编程的另一个特性
And for this we're going to leverage another feature of programming,
特别是某些功能的一个特征 即它们
specifically a feature of some functions, which is that they
也可以有返回值
can have return values as well.
如果你再一次把输入看作是这个动作
If you think of input as being, again, this action,
这个动词--你实际上可以把它拟人化成一个人
this verb-- you can actually personify it as maybe a person,
就像你的一个朋友 你问了一个问题
like a friend of yours that you've asked a question of
你让你的朋友去征求别人的意见--
and you've asked your friend to go get input from someone else--
去问问那个人他们的名字
go ask that person their name.
如果你的朋友回来时知道了那个人的名字
And if your friend comes back knowing that person's name, well,
如果他们把那个名字还给你不是很好吗？
wouldn't it be nice if they handed that name back to you?
比喻地说 这就是我们需要的功能
That's kind of what we need metaphorically the function to do,
就是获得用户的输入 然后把它交回给我 这样我 作为程序员
is get the user's input and then hand it back to me so that I, the programmer,
可以用它做点什么
can do something with it.
但如果要还给我的话
But if it's going to be handed back to me,
我有点想把它放在某个地方 这样我就可以把它打印回来了
I kind of want to put it somewhere so that I can then print it back
在屏幕上
on the screen.
我需要做的相当于拿出一张纸或便利贴
I need to do the equivalent of take out like a piece of paper or Post-It note,
在这张纸上写下人类说过的话
write down on this piece of paper what it is the human has said,
这样我就可以将其作为输入输入到打印功能中
so that I can then feed it into as input that print function.
要做到这一点 我们将需要编程的另一个功能 即
And to do that, we're going to need one more feature of programming, namely
变量
variables.
可能性是 大多数人都熟悉数学课上的变量
And odds are, most everyone's familiar with variables from math class
很久以前--x y z等等
way back when-- x and y and z and the like.
嗯 编程也有同样的能力 这种能力
Well, programming has that same capability, this ability
要创建一个变量--在这个例子中 是在计算机的内存中--
to create a variable-- in this case, in the computer's memory--
不仅仅是在一张纸上
not just on a piece of paper.
该变量可以存储一个值--
And that variable can store a value--
一个数字 一些文本 甚至一个图像或视频或更多
a number, some text, even an image or video or more.
变量只是计算机内部某个值的容器
A variable is just a container for some value inside of a computer
或者在你自己的程序中
or inside of your own program.
那么 我该如何用这种方式来表达自己呢？
So how do I go about expressing myself in this way?
我想我要做的是介绍
Well I think what I'm going to do is introduce
一个名称比x或y更有趣的变量
a variable that's a little more interestingly named than x or y.
我可以这么说--x=输入
I could just say this-- x = input.
但我将在这里使用一个比典型数学变量更好的名称
But I'm going to use a better name than a typical mathematical variable here
我要把我的变量按字面意思命名为“名称” 为什么？
and I'm going to literally call my variable "name," why?
在编程方面 因为我面前有一个完整的键盘
Well in programming, because I have a whole keyboard in front of me,
我可以用更具描述性的术语来描述我正在写的东西
I can use more descriptive terms to describe what it is I'm writing.
然而 现在有机会考虑一段特定的语法
And now, though, there's an opportunity to consider a specific piece of syntax.
我们看到了圆括号 我们看到了引号 所有这些
We've seen parentheses, we've seen quotes, all of which
在将输入传递给函数时是必需的
are necessary when passing inputs to a function,
但是这个等号在右边的输入和名字之间
but this equal sign here that's in between input on the right and name
左翼实际上很重要
on the left is actually important.
从技术上讲 它本身并不是等号
And it's technically not an equal sign per se.
与其说它意味着平等 不如说它意味着分配
It doesn't mean equality as much as it means assignment.
因此 在Python和许多编程语言中
So in Python and many programming languages,
单个等号是赋值运算符
a single equal sign is the assignment operator
具体来说 这意味着 你
and what that means specifically is that, you
我想从右到左分配用户输入的任何内容
want to assign from right to left whatever the user's input is.
所以等号从右到左复制 不管返回
So the equal sign copies from the right to the left whatever the return
右侧函数的值为
value of the function on the right is.
因此 输入函数显然是从用户那里获得输入的
So again, the input function clearly gets input from the user.
这就是为什么我能够输入我的名字或卡特的名字 但它也
That's why I was able to type my name or Carter's, but it also
有点像是在幕后把那个值 那个返回值 交给我
sort of behind the scenes hands that value, that return value, back to me
程序员
the programmer.
如果我使用等号和变量 不管我怎么称呼它
And if I use an equal sign and a variable, no matter what I call it,
我可以将该输入存储在该变量中 以便以后重复使用
I can store that input in that variable so as to reuse it later.
所以现在 坐在计算机内存中的某个地方
So now, sitting in the computer's memory somewhere,
是包含“David”引号、非引号或“Carter”引号的容器
is a container containing "David" quote, unquote or "Carter" quote,
不引用 或人类输入的任何内容
unquote, or whatever the human has typed in.
但在这里 很容易犯错误
But here it's easy to make a mistake.
假设我决定打印这个名字 所以
Suppose I decide to try to print that name and so
我有种预感 你好 名字
I kind of on a hunch type in this, hello, name.
只是输入变量的名称
Just kind of plugging in the name of the variable.
现在让我继续运行Hello.py的Python 然后按Enter键
Well let me go ahead here and run Python of Hello.py and hit Enter.
这会提示我输入我的名字
That's going to prompt me for my name.
让我输入我的名字--
And let me type in my name--
D-A-V-I-D 但我还没有按回车键
D-A-V-I-D. But I haven't hit Enter yet.
也许通过聊天 当我现在按Enter键时 这里会发生什么？
And perhaps via the chat, what's going to happen here when I now hit Enter?
我希望它能说 你好 大卫
I'm hoping it says, Hello, David.
如果它说Hello world 我会很好 但我不想让它说它实际上是什么
I'd be OK if it says Hello, world, but I don't want it to say what it's actually
我们在聊天中看到的是
going to say and, yep, what we're seeing in the chat is,
它可能会直接说你好 名字.
well, it's probably going to say literally Hello, name.
所以这并不完全正确
So that's not quite right.
所以我们需要另一种方法来打印变量的值
So we need another way of printing out the value inside of that variable
而不仅仅是“名字”这个词“
rather than just this word "name."
让我用几种不同的方式来尝试一下
Well let me try this in a couple of different ways.
让我试着这样做
Let me try this as follows--
让我继续 也许撤销这一点 因为我已经得到了相当不错的
let me go ahead and maybe undo this because I've gotten pretty good already
打招呼
at saying Hello.
所以我们划清界限 好吧
So let's draw that line in the sand and just say, all right,
我们至少把你好逗号赶出家门吧
let's get at least get Hello comma out the door.
现在让我们打印姓名 凭直觉 我将尝试这样做
Let's now print name and just on a hunch, I'm going to try this.
我将再次使用打印--
I'm going to use print again--
因为你可以根据需要多次使用这些函数
because you can use these functions as many times as you need--
我将把名为name的变量传递给print函数
and I'm going to pass to the print function the variable called name.
但请注意我现在有点聪明了
But notice I'm being a little clever now.
我没有把它放在双引号里 因为我们已经看到了双引号
I'm not putting it in double quotes because we've seen already that double
引号的意思是打印出来
quotes means literally print out N-A-M-E.
我这次去掉引号是希望
I'm getting rid of the quotes this time in hopes that,
现在通过将变量name传递给函数print
now by passing the variable called name to the function called print it will,
实际上 打印变量的内容
in fact, go about printing the contents of that variable that is,
所谓的价值
its so-called value.
好吧 我们就在这里开始吧
All right, let's go ahead and do this here.
Hello.py的Python 输入
Python of Hello.py, Enter.
你叫什麽名字？
What's your name?
大卫
David.
现在 我仍然交叉手指 我看到你好逗号大卫
And now, crossing my fingers still, I see Hello comma David.
好吧
All right.
所以这不是最好的方案
So it's not the best program.
可以说 我是在偷工减料
I'm kind of cutting some corners here, so to speak.
我在两条线上说你好 大卫
I'm saying Hello, David on two separate lines.
所以它不那么优雅 不那么漂亮
So it's not as elegant, it's not as pretty,
在英语中 它不像直接说出来那样符合语法
it's not as grammatically appropriate in English as just saying it
所有在一个呼吸在一行 但至少我已经解决了这个问题 只是没有
all in one breath on one line, but at least I've solved the problem, just not
还很好
very well yet.
但现在让我退一步
But let me take a step back now and perhaps introduce
我们应该熟悉的其他几个概念
a couple of other concepts with which we should be familiar,
这是因为我们的程序变得更长 它们不再只有一两行
which is as our programs get longer and they're no longer just one line or two
甚至三个 我们的节目最终会变成几十行
or even three, eventually our programs are going to become dozens of lines,
甚至可能有数百行之长
maybe even hundreds of lines long.
让我们为未来的成功铺平道路
Let's set the stage for success moving forward.
事实证明 Python和许多编程语言
It turns out that Python and a lot of programming languages
也支持一种叫做评论的东西
also support something called comments.
注释是代码中对您自己的注释
Comments are notes to yourself in your code
并且您可以通过特殊符号--在Python中--来包含注释
and you include comments by way of a special symbol-- in Python
它将是散列符号 通常是--
it's going to be the hash symbol, typically--
这样你就可以写出等价的
and that allows you to write the equivalent
一张纸条给你自己 但不会破坏你的代码
of a note to yourself but in a way that's not going to break your code.
电脑实际上会忽略你的评论
The computer actually ignores your comment.
它就在你的身边 就在你的老师身边
It's just there for you, it's just there for your teacher,
它就在那里 只等着你的同事
it's just there for your colleague with whom
你最终是在分享这段代码
you're sharing ultimately that code.
所以如果我回到这里的VS代码 我只是
So if I go back to VS Code here and I just
我想给这个节目添加一些评论 向我的老师解释一下
want to add some comments to this program to explain to my teacher,
对我自己 对我的同事们 这个项目正在做的事情
to myself, to my colleagues what this program is doing,
好吧 那我们就这么做吧
well, let's go ahead and do that.
我将在我的程序的最顶端 在第一行
I'm going to go at the very top of my program and on line 1
现在 我将把原来的代码行向下移动一点
now I'm going to move that original line of code down a bit,
我将添加一个散列 我将这样说
I'm going to add a hash, and I'm going to say something like this,
要求用户输入他们的姓名
ask user for their name.
现在 我不需要用那种语言
Now, I don't have to use that language.
我不需要用那条短信
I don't have to use that text.
我可以使用任何人类语言
I could use any human language whatsoever.
它不一定是英语
It doesn't have to be English.
但我现在要说的是 在那个下面 只说这样的话--
But I'm going to now, below that, just say something like this--
向用户问好
say Hello to user.
您会注意到 默认情况下 VS代码
And you'll notice that VS Code by default
让我的评论变灰了
is kind of graying out my comments.
它们不再是蓝色 不再是红色 也不再是颜色
They're no longer blue, there's no red, there's no color in them.
这只是因为它们是对我自己的笔记
And that's just because they're notes to myself
而计算机最终会忽略它们
and the computer ultimately is going to ignore them.
但我们现在有两条评论--询问用户
But what we have now is two comments-- ask user
对于他们的名字 然后是第二条评论 向用户问好
for their name and then a second comment, say Hello to user.
我刚刚注释了每一段代码
And I've just kind of commented each chunk of code,
就像每一行或多行复数代码一样 它们正在做一些值得注意的事情
like each line or lines plural of code, that are doing something noteworthy.
为什么？
Why?
好吧 明天早上当我醒来的时候
Well, tomorrow morning when I wake up having
睡了好一阵子 忘了前一天做了什么
slept for quite some time, forgotten what it is I did the previous day,
评论很方便 只需查看
it's convenient with comments to just see
用英语或你自己的人类语言
in English or your own human language what
这是一个程序 这样你就不需要阅读代码本身了
it is this program is doing so that you don't have to read the code itself
而且 更好的是 如果未来可能出现错误
and, better yet, if there's maybe a mistake down the road,
您可以阅读您的意图 然后您可以查看代码
you can read what your intention was and then you can look at the code
并确定您的代码现在是否正在执行您想要的操作
and figure out if your code is now doing what you intended.
因此 对于这么小的程序来说 这并不是真正必要的
So this isn't really necessary for a program this small.
很明显 只有一行、两行或三行
It's pretty obvious with just one or two or three lines
程序在做什么
what the program is doing.
阅读代码的速度和阅读注释一样快
It's just as fast to read the code than the comments,
但养成这个习惯通常是一件好事--
but getting into this habit is generally a good thing--
每隔一行或几行注释代码 以提醒自己
to comment your code every one or a few lines so as to remind yourself
以及其他是您的意图和您的代码正在做什么
and others what it is your intent and your code is doing.
评论的好处也在于--
What's nice about comments too is this--
评论也可以成为你自己的待办事项清单
comments can also serve to be sort of a to-do list for yourself.
在伪代码编程中有这样一个概念
There's this notion in programming of pseudocode.
伪码不是一种正式的东西
Pseudocode isn't a formal thing.
它不是一种特定的语言
It's not one specific language.
它只是使用英语或你自己的人类语言
It's just using English or your own human language
简洁、有条不紊、有算法地表达你的想法
to express your thoughts succinctly, methodically, algorithmically,
可以这么说
so to speak.
但是伪代码 因此 因为它不是Python
But pseudocode, therefore, because it's not Python
它不一定是英语 它只是一种允许
and it's not necessarily English, it just kind of allows
你甚至需要提前概述你的计划.
you to outline your program even in advance.
举个例子 如果我今天不确定如何
So for instance, if I wasn't sure today how
我想着手写这个程序
I wanted to go about writing this program
但我不知道我想做什么 我本可以从今天开始
but I didn't know what I wanted to do, I could have started today
只需在Hello.py中编写这段代码
by just writing this in Hello.py.
没有代码 我可以只对自己写几条评论--
No code, I could have written just a couple of comments to myself--
步骤1 询问用户姓名
Step 1, ask user for their name.
第二步 向用户问好
Step 2, say Hello to user.
然后 一旦我用伪代码概述了我的程序 然后我就可以进去了
Then once I've outlined my program in pseudocode, then I can go in there
然后说 好吧 我怎么向用户询问他们的名字呢？
and say, all right, how do I ask the user for their name?
好吧 我可以输入“你叫什么名字”的问题？
Well, I can do input "what's your name" question?
然后在左边 我可以放一个变量 然后把它赋值给它
And then on the left here, I can maybe put a variable and assign it to that.
好的 我该如何向用户问好呢？
OK, how do I say Hello to the user?
嗯 我知道我可以用印刷体在屏幕上说些什么
Well, I know I can use print to say things on the screen.
让我打个招呼 让我--
Let me say hello, and let me--
好的 现在让我把这个人的名字打印出来
OK, let me now print the person's name.
因此 伪代码是构建待办事项列表的一种很好的方式
So again, pseudocode is a nice way of structuring your to-do list,
尤其是如果您不知道如何编写代码
especially if you have no idea how to write the code,
因为它将一个较大的程序分解成几个小任务
because it breaks a bigger program down into small bite-sized tasks.
好吧 让我在这里停一下 看看现在有没有
All right, let me pause here to see if there are now
有关注释、伪代码、返回值或变量的任何问题
any questions on comments, pseudocode, return values, or variables.
有什么问题我们可以在这里说清楚吗？
Any questions we can clear up here?
听众：是的 我的问题是功能输入
AUDIENCE: Yeah, my question is does the function input
为任何类型的信息工作 还是只为文字工作？
work for any type of information, or only for words?
大卫·马兰：是的 这个问题问得很好
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, really good question.
所以根据它的文档 我们将更多地查看正式文档
So according to its documentation, and we'll look more at formal documentation
很快 输入将会期待所谓的
soon, input is going to expect what's called
一个字符串 那是一个文本序列 不管它是什么
a string, that is a sequence of text, be it
用英语或任何其他人类语言
in English or any other human language.
但它确实会期待用来提示用户的文本
But it's indeed going to be expecting text with which to prompt the user.
问得好
A good question.
如果可以的话 小组里的另一个问题怎么样？
How about another question from the group, if we could?
观众：我想问的是 我该如何发表几行评论呢？
AUDIENCE: I wanted to ask how would I make a several line comment?
大卫·马兰：哦 你是怎么做很多评论的
DAVID MALAN: Oh, how do you do many lines of comments,
如果我没听错的话？
if I'm hearing you correctly?
观众：是的
AUDIENCE: Yes.
大卫·马兰：当然
DAVID MALAN: Sure.
你就会一直这样做下去
You would just keep doing them like this.
您只需为每行添加一个散列符号前缀 就像我在这里所做的那样
You just prefix each of the lines with a hash symbol, like I'm doing here.
还有另一种在Python中执行多行注释的技术 即
There is another technique for doing multi-line comments in Python that
实际上往往有特殊的含义
actually tend to have special meaning.
你可以像这样做三个双引号 然后在这里做任何中间的事情
You can do three double quotes like this and then anything in between here
是一种评论
is a comment.
这是另一种技术
That's another technique.
或者 您也可以使用单引号
Or you can use single quotes as well.
但我认为 下次会有更多关于这些的内容
But more on those, I think, another time.
好吧 好吧 你不会介意的 让我继续
All right, well, you don't mind, let me forge ahead here
看看我们可以如何进一步改进这个项目
and see how we might improve this program further
还介绍了一些其他功能 我们可能
and also introduce a few other features that we might
想要考虑到随着时间的推移
want to take into account over time.
所以事实证明 我们肯定可以改进这个项目
So it turns out that we can certainly improve on this program
因为我在这里偷工减料有点令人失望
because it's a little disappointing that I'm cutting this corner
然后说你好 逗号 然后在新的一行打印出名字
and saying Hello comma and then on a new line printing out name.
好像我们能做得更好
Like we can do better.
当然 你在手机或笔记本上使用的大多数程序
And most programs you use on your phone or your laptop certainly
当人们需要时 将文本放在一起
keep text together when people want.
那么 我们该如何着手做这件事呢？
So how can we go about doing that?
嗯 有几种不同的方法
Well there's a few different ways.
事实上 这里的目标并不是要解决这个问题
And in fact, the goal here is not so much to solve this one problem,
但为了在编程中演示和强调这一点--
but to demonstrate and emphasize that in programming--
Python和其他语言--有很多方法
Python and other languages-- there's so many ways
有时是为了解决同样的问题
sometimes to solve the same problem.
这里有一个解决这个问题的方法
And here's one way to solve this problem.
让我进去 现在让我来打个招呼
Let me go in here and let me go ahead now and say hello,
让我在该用户名的末尾添加
and let me just add to the end of that the user's name.
所以我正在以一种有趣的方式使用+
So I'm using + in kind of an interesting way.
本质上 这不是加法
This is not addition, per se.
很明显 我不是在加数字 但我确实加了
I'm not adding numbers, obviously, but I do
我想把这个人的名字加到逗号字符串中
kind of want to add the person's name to the string of text Hello comma.
现在让我转到我的终端窗口并运行Hello.py的Python
Well let me go now down to my terminal window and run Python of Hello.py
再次输入
again, Enter.
你叫什么名字？
What's your name?
我要把大卫打进去
I'm going to type in David.
进来吧
Enter.
好了 好多了
OK, it's better.
这是更好的 但有一个小错误 尽管这里的美学
It's better, but there's a minor bug, albeit aesthetic here.
这里缺少空白处 但让我们在这里使用一些直觉
There's missing space, but let's just use some intuition here.
好吧 如果我漏掉了逗号后面的空格
Well, if I'm missing the space after the comma,
为什么我不在这里手动添加它呢？
why don't I go ahead and just add it manually here.
现在让我重新运行程序Hello.py的Python Enter David Enter
Let me now rerun the program Python of Hello.py, Enter, David, Enter.
这就对了
And there we go.
现在我们有了一些看起来更漂亮的东西
Now we have something that looks a little prettier
在英语语法方面
in terms of English grammar.
你好 逗号 空格 大卫
Hello, comma, space, David.
现在如果我们倒带 你可能已经注意到了
And now if we rewind, you might have noticed before
或者想知道为什么我的问号后面有这个看似多余的空格
or wondered why I had this seemingly extra space after my question mark,
也就是这里
namely here.
问号后、双引号前有一个空格
There's a space after the question mark but before the double quote
这也只是为了美观
and that was just for aesthetics too.
我想将用户的光标向右移动一个空间
I wanted to move the user's cursor one space to the right
所以当我输入他们的名字或他们输入他们的名字时
so that when I typed their name or they typed their name,
它不是紧挨着那个问号的
it's not immediately next to that same question mark there.
但我们还有其他方法可以做到这一点
But there's other ways we can do this.
事实证明 一些函数 其中包括打印
It turns out that some functions, print among them,
实际上有多个论据
actually take multiple arguments.
事实证明 如果你把输入分离出来
And it turns out that if you separate the inputs
函数--即函数的所谓参数--加上逗号
to a function-- the so-called arguments to a function-- with a comma,
你不能只传一次 还可以传两次 三次 四次 五次 往前
you can pass in not just one, but two, three, four, five, onward.
所以让我继续下去 不仅仅是你好 逗号 空格 还有随后的
So let me go ahead and pass in not just hello, comma, space, but that followed
叫出名字
by name.
乍一看 这可能有点令人困惑
And this is a little confusing potentially at first glance
因为现在我有两个逗号 但需要注意的是
because now I've got two commas but it's important to note
第一个逗号在我的引号内 这只是
that the first comma is inside of my quotation marks, which is simply
一种符合英语语法的东西
an English grammatical thing.
第二个逗号在引号之外
The second comma here is outside of the quotes,
但现在有两种不同的论据需要发表
but between what are now two separate arguments to print.
第一个参数是Hello、逗号、空格
The first argument is hello, comma, space.
第二个参数是名称变量本身
The second argument is the name variable itself.
所以让我们来看看这是什么样子
So let's see how this looks.
Python of Hello.py 回车
Python of Hello.py, Enter.
你叫什么名字？
What's your name?
大卫
David.
进来吧
Enter.
好吧 我有点矫枉过正了
OK, I've kind of over-corrected.
出于某种原因 我现在有两个车位
Now I've got two spaces for some reason.
事实证明 这是微妙的 当
Well, it turns out, and this is subtle, when
您将多个参数传递给print 它会自动为您插入一个空格
you pass multiple arguments to print, it automatically inserts a space for you.
这件事之前并不重要 因为我
This was not relevant earlier because I was
通过使用+运算符 传入一个大参数以一次性打印所有内容
passing in one big argument to print all at once by using that + operator.
这一次 由于逗号的原因 我传入了两个
This time I'm passing in two because of the comma.
因此 如果我不想要额外的空间 我不需要自己传递一个空间
So if I don't want that extra space, I don't need to pass in one myself,
我可以这样做 现在注意到 如果我再次运行这个程序--
I can just do this and now notice, if I run this program again--
Python of Hello.py 输入我的名字David
Python of Hello.py, type in my name David,
现在 从语法上看 它可能是我想要的
now it looks grammatically like I might want.
现在 这些方法中哪一种更好？
Now which of these approaches is better?
这种方法使用带有两个参数的函数print--
This approach uses a function print with two arguments--
你好 逗号和名称变量
Hello, comma and the name variable.
之前的版本 Recall 技术上使用了一个论点
The previous version, recall, technically used one argument,
尽管它看起来有点奇怪
even though it looked a little curious.
这是一种观点 计算机就像数学家一样
It's one argument in the sense that the computer, just like mathematicians,
我们首先要做的是括号内的内容
are going to do what's inside of parentheses first.
所以如果你在圆括号里有这串文字--
So if inside of parentheses you have this string of text--
你好 逗号和空格 我需要添加回来
hello, comma, and a space, which I need to add back.
然后你有一个+ 这意味着本身不是加法
Then you have a +, which means not addition, per se,
而是串联--把左边的东西和右边的东西连接起来
but concatenation-- to join the thing on the left and the thing on the right.
这最终变成了英语短语--
This ultimately becomes the English phrase--
你好 逗号 空格 大卫
Hello, comma, space, David.
然后最终传递给函数的是什么
And then what's being passed ultimately to the function
从技术上讲是这样的 但它完全是动态的
is technically something like this, but it's doing it all dynamically.
这不是我像之前那样小心翼翼地输入大卫
It's not me typing in David as I discreetly did earlier.
它会动态计算出连接Hello后的值
It's figuring out dynamically what that value is after concatenating Hello
使用名称的值 然后最终传递
with the value of name and then passing that ultimately
作为唯一的论据发表
to print as the sole argument.
让我在这里暂停一下 看看是否有任何关于论点数量的问题
Let me pause here to see if there's any questions on numbers of arguments
现在 让我们来谈谈功能
now to functions.
观众：我们可以多次使用一个函数吗
AUDIENCE: Can we use a function many times
来解决我们在代码中可能多次遇到的某个问题？
to solve a certain problem which we can encounter many times in our code?
大卫·马兰：你可以的
DAVID MALAN: You can.
您可以多次使用一个函数来解决某些问题
You can use a function many different times to solve some problem.
不过 我们很快就会看到 如果你发现自己
What we'll soon see, though, is if you find yourself
当程序员再次以相同的方式解决问题时
as the programmer solving a problem the same way again,
再一次 一次又一次 事实证明你会
and again, and again, it turns out you'll
能够做出自己的功能 这样你就可以
be able to make your own function so that you
不必一直重复使用语言附带的基本功能
don't have to keep reusing the basic ones that come with the language.
观众：我对逗号和+号很好奇
AUDIENCE: I was curious about the comma and the + sign.
所以在+号之后 我们能不能只给出一个变量 在逗号之后再给我们
So after + sign, can we give just one variable and after comma again we
是否提供多变量状态？
give multiple variable status?
有什么关系？
What is the difference?
大卫·马兰：问得好
DAVID MALAN: A good question.
因此 在弦的上下文中--
So in the context of strings--
我一直在用这个词
and I keep using that term.
“字符串”是编程语言中的一个技术术语
"String" is a technical term in a programming language
同样 它意味着一系列文本--一个字符 一个单词 整个段落
and again, it means a sequence of text-- a character, a word, a whole paragraph,
不相上下
even.
所以不只是使用+运算符 我们将
So the + operator is not just used, as we'll
看 对于在Python中的数字加法 就像我们在纸铅笔上做的那样
see, for addition of numbers in Python, like we do on paper pencil,
但它也用于连接左侧和右侧的字符串
but it also is used for concatenation of strings on the left and the right.
如果你想组合的不只是两根弦--
If you did want to combine not just two strings--
左和右--但第三和第四个
left and right-- but a third and a fourth,
您完全可以继续使用+、+ 并将它们链接在一起
you can absolutely keep using +, +, +, +, and chain them together
就像在数学里一样
just like in math.
最终 这会开始看起来有点丑陋
Eventually that's going to start to look a little ugly,
我敢说 特别是当您的代码行变得很长的时候
I dare say, especially if your line of code gets long.
所以有更好的方法 我们很快就会看到
So there's better ways that we'll actually soon see.
也是一个很好的问题
And a good question as well.
好的 让我回到这里讨论的代码
Well let me come back to the code here in question
看看我们能不能给你们展示几种其他的方式
and see if we can show you just a couple of other ways
来解决同样的问题 同时强调我们在技术上
to solve the same problem, along the way emphasizing that what we're technically
说到这里 是的 是弦 但甚至还有
talking about here, yes, are strings, but there's even
在Python中表示这些字符串的技术术语
a technical term for these strings in Python,
这就是STR 可以说 S-T-R 简称为弦
it's just STR, so to speak, S-T-R for short, for string.
如果你用其他语言编程 你可能知道
As you may know if you programmed in other languages,
发明编程语言的人喜欢非常简洁
people who invent programming languages like to be very succinct, to the point,
所以我们倾向于用相当简短的短语来描述事物
so we tend to use fairly short phrases to describe things,
不一定是完整的单词
not necessarily full words.
所以 虽然你可能会说“弦” 从技术上讲
So while you might say "string," technically
在Python语言中 我们真正谈论的是这些文本序列
in Python what we're really talking about, these sequences of text,
严格来说是STR
are technically STRs.
这是程序中的实际数据类型
This is an actual type of data in a program.
但我们很快就会发现 程序中还有其他类型的数据
But we'll soon see that there's other types of data in programs as well.
事实上 让我们看看我们是否不能用另一种方式来改善这一点
In fact, let's see if we can't improve this in one other way.
我喜欢我们通过让一切保持一致而取得的进展--
I like the progress we've made by keeping everything on the same line--
你好 大卫在同一条线路上
Hello, David all on the same line.
然而 在解决这个问题方面 我们还能做些什么呢？
What more though could we do in terms of solving this problem?
嗯 事实证明 我们并不需要完全放弃
Well, it turns out that we didn't have to give up entirely
使用打印两次
with using print twice.
让我倒回一点 回到以前的版本
Let me rewind a little bit and go back to that earlier version
我真的不确定如何解决这个问题 所以我使用了一次打印
where I wasn't really sure how to solve this problem so I was using print once
只打印出Hello、空格和逗号
to print out just the Hello and the space and the comma.
然后我再次使用打印来打印姓名
And then I used print again to print name.
严格地说 这并不坏 但有一个视觉副作用
That's, strictly speaking, wasn't bad, but there was this visual side effect
这是我不喜欢的
that I didn't like.
把这两行文字分开看起来很难看
It just looked ugly to have these two lines of text separate
彼此之间的距离
from one another.
但还有另一种方法可以解决这个问题
But there's another way to fix this.
显然 打印功能似乎是自动
Clearly it seems to be the case that the print function is automatically
输出一个空行
outputting a blank line.
它会自动将光标移动到下一行
It's moving the cursor automatically for me to the next line
因为这就是为什么我在一条线路上看到Hello和David
because that's why I'm seeing Hello on one line and David
在下一个问题上 然后是我的提示--
on the next and then my prompt--
美元符号--在下面的那条线上
the dollar sign-- on the line below that.
因此 印刷品似乎在自动推定
So print seems to be presuming automatically
您希望它将光标移动到下一行
that you want it to move the cursor to the next line
在你给它传递一些参数之后
after you pass it some argument.
但您可以覆盖该行为
But you can override that behavior.
同样 函数接受影响其行为的参数
Again, functions take arguments which influence their behavior,
你只需要知道这些论点是什么
you just have to know what those arguments are.
事实证明 如果我们查看有关Python打印的文档
And it turns out that if we look at the documentation for Python's print
函数 我们实际上可以在这里查看这个URL--
function, we can actually look up at this URL here--
在docs.python.org上可以找到所有的Python官方文档
docs.python.org is where all of Python's official documentation lies.
如果我四处看看 我可以找到更具体的这个URL
If I poke around, I can find my way to more specifically this URL
在这里 我可以找到所有可用的Python函数
here where I can find all of the available functions in Python
以及那里的文档
and the documentation there for.
如果我走得更准确一点 我甚至可以
And if I go a little more precisely, I can even
查找打印函数本身的特定文档
find specific documentation for the print function itself.
而不是在浏览器中打开它
And rather than pull that up in a browser,
接下来 我将突出显示同一URL中的一行 即
I'm going to go ahead and highlight just one line from that same URL, which
这是我们所见过的最神秘的东西
is this, and this is easily the most cryptic thing we've seen yet,
但这是打印功能的官方文档
but this is the official documentation for the print function.
在学习编程语言时 你能做的最好的事情之一就是
And one of the best things you can do when learning a programming language
老实说 就是学会阅读文档
is, honestly, learn to read the documentation,
因为真的 你所有问题的答案都会以某种方式
because truly, all of the answers to your questions will in some way
尽管不可否认 这并不总是显而易见的 但一定要做到
be there, even though, admittedly, it's not always obvious.
我也会说 Python的文档
And I will say too, Python's documentation
这不一定是最容易的事情 特别是对于第一次或新手来说
isn't necessarily the easiest thing, especially for a first time or novice
程序员
programmer.
这也需要练习 所以如果你不是这样的话 试着不要感到不知所措
It too just takes practice, so try not to get overwhelmed if you're not
当然你看到的是什么
sure what you're looking at.
但让我向您介绍一下这个例子
But let me walk you through this example.
这也是来自Python官方文档的一行文本
This again is a line of text from Python's official documentation
用于打印功能
for the print function.
这表明这是这样的--
What this indicates as follows is this--
这个函数的名称当然是print
the name of this function is, of course print.
然后这里有一个括号和另一种紧凑的括号方式
Then there's a parenthesis over here and another close parenthesis way
在那边
over there.
这些括号中的所有内容都是
Everything inside of those parentheses are
参数 潜在的参数 传递给函数
the arguments, the potential arguments, to the function.
然而 当我们看到这些论点时
However, when we're looking at these arguments
在这样的文档中 从技术上讲 有一个不同的术语
in the documentation like this, there's technically a different term
我们会用到的
that we would use.
从技术上讲 这些是该函数的参数
These are technically the parameters to the function.
因此 当您谈论可以传递给函数的内容时
So when you're talking about what you can pass to a function
这些输入被称为什么 这些就是参数
and what those inputs are called, those are parameters.
当您实际使用该函数并传递
When you actually use the function and pass
在这些圆括号内的值中 这些输入
in values inside of those parentheses, those inputs,
这些值是参数
those values are arguments.
所以我们谈论的是完全相同的事情--参数和自变量
So we're talking about the exact same thing-- parameters and arguments are
实际上是一样的 但你的条款
effectively the same thing, but the terms you
从不同的角度看问题的用处
use from looking at the problem from different directions.
当我们查看该函数可以采用的功能与
When we're looking at what the function can take versus what
您实际上是在传递到函数中
you're actually passing into the function.
那么 这意味着什么呢？
So what does this imply?
这个语法相当隐晦 但目前
Well this syntax is pretty cryptic, but at the moment,
只要知道一个星号 一个星星 然后是“物体”这个词
just know that an asterisk, a star, and then the word "objects"
意味着打印函数可以接受任意数量的对象
means that the print function can take any number of objects.
您可以传入0个文本字符串 1个字符串
You can pass in 0 strings of text, one string
就像我做的那样 两根弦 或者 从技术上讲 无限多根弦
like I did, two strings like I did, or, technically, infinitely many
如果您真的想要 尽管代码看起来不会很好
if you really want, though that code is not going to look very good.
在那之后我们看到一个逗号 然后我们在这里看到另一个参数
After that we see a comma, then we see another parameter here
被称为SEP 在英语中是分离器的缩写
called SEP, short for separator in English.
注意等号和单引号 空格 单引号
And notice the equal sign and the single quote, space, single quote.
所以“太空”我还不知道那是什么
So 'space' I don't know what that is yet,
但我认为我们已经看到了这方面的暗示
but I think we've seen a hint about it.
让我们暂时把注意力集中在这个--
Let's focus though for a moment on this--
打印函数接受另一个名为end的参数和默认参数
the print function takes another parameter called end and the default
该参数值显然是基于这个等号和这些
value of that parameter is apparently, based on this equal sign and these
引号 /n
quotes, /n.
如果你想加入聊天 那/n是什么？
And what is /n, if you'd like to chime in in the chat?
以前编程的人可能都看过这个
Anyone who's program before has probably seen this,
不过 如果您以前从未编写过程序 这看起来可能会非常神秘
though if you've never programmed before, this might look quite cryptic.
反斜杠n表示换行 这是一种文本方式
Backslash n means new line, and it's a way textually
表明你是否以及何时有效地想要电脑
of indicating if and when you want the computer effectively
要将光标移动到下一行 请创建新的文本行
to move the cursor to the next line, create a new line of text.
因此 从技术上讲 如果我们阅读文档
And so technically, if we read into the documentation,
我们将看到关于这一点的更多细节
we'll see more detail on this.
事实上 在打印文档中有一个名为end的参数
The fact that there's a parameter called end in the documentation for the print
函数 这意味着默认情况下 此打印函数将结束
function, just means that by default this print function is going to end
每一行都有/n
every line with /n.
你看到的不是字面上的/n 而是一个新的行
You don't literally see /n, you see a new line.
您会看到光标移动到下一行
You see the cursor moving to the next line.
现在按照这个逻辑 让我们后退一步
Now by that logic, let's move backwards.
SEP Four分隔符--分隔符的缺省值
SEP four separator-- the default value of separator
显然是一个空格
is apparently a single blank space.
那么 我们在哪里看到的呢？
Well where have we seen that?
回想一下前面的一个例子 我传入的不只是一个 而是两个
Well recall in an earlier example when I passed in not just one but two
Print函数的参数
arguments to the print function.
回想一下 他们之间有一个神奇的空间
Recall that they magically had a space between them.
事实上 他们有那个空间+我自己的空间
In fact, they had that space + my own space
这就是为什么我删除了我的空间 因为在这一点上它是额外的
and that's why I deleted my space because at that point it was extra.
因此 这只是意味着当您将多个参数传递给print时 默认情况下
So this just means that when you pass multiple arguments to print, by default
它们将被一个空格隔开
they're going to be separated by a single space.
默认情况下 当您将参数传递给print时
By default, when you pass arguments to print,
整件事都将以一句新台词结束
it's the whole thing is going to be ended with a new line.
现在 只要知道这一点 让我从字面上
Now just by knowing this, and let me literally
把我的手放在剩下的文件上 改天再说
wave my hand at the rest of the documentation for another day,
印刷品可以做的事情还有很多 但我们
there's more things that print can do, but we're
我们将重点放在SEP上 让我们看看我们现在是否不能利用这一点
going to focus just on SEP and on END, let's see if we can't leverage this now
来解决这个最初的问题
to solve that original problem.
最初的问题是这样的 我不喜欢你好 大卫
The original problem was this, I don't like how Hello, David
在两条不同的线路上
is on two different lines.
好吧 这又发生了 因为指纹是自动的
Well that's happening again because print is automatically
打印出一个新的行 所以让我们告诉它不要这样做
printing out a new line, so let's tell it not to do that.
让我们通过向第一次使用print传递第二个参数来说明这一点
Let's tell it by passing a second argument to the first use of PRINT
说结束=引用 不引用--
to say END = quote, unquote--
NOT/N 这是自动设置的默认值
not /n, which is the default automatically.
让我们引用它 不引用其他任何东西
Let's make it quote, unquote nothing else.
让我们覆盖缺省值 这样就不会有新行了
Let's override the default value so there is no new line.
从字面上看什么都没有
There's literally nothing there.
让我们看看会发生什么
And let's see what happens.
现在让我转到我的终端窗口并清除它
Let me now go down to my terminal window and clear it.
我将运行Hello.py的Python 回车
And I'm going to run Python of Hello.py, Enter.
我要输入我的名字 大卫和我
I'm going to type in my name, David and I
我想现在一切都会保持一致 因为--
think now everything is going to stay on the same line because--
它做到了--这一行 5 将打印出Hello 逗号 空格
and it did-- this line here, 5, is going to print out Hello, comma, space,
但最后什么都没有 因为我
but then nothing at the end of it because I
改成了引用 不引用
changed it to be quote, unquote.
第二行将打印名字 大卫
The second line is going to print the name, David,
或者不管这个人的名字是什么 它会将光标移动到下一行
or whatever the human's name is, and it will move the cursor to the next line
因为我没有覆盖End There的值
because I didn't override the value of END there.
为了更清楚地看到这一点 如果你做一些神秘的事情
Just to see this more explicitly, if you do something cryptic like,
我不知道发生了什么事
well I have no idea what's going on.
让我暂时在这里加三个问号
Let me just put in temporarily three question marks here.
我们也会看到这一结果的
We'll see the results of this too.
让我返回到我的终端窗口 运行问候的Python Py
Let me go back down to my terminal window, run Python of hello. py,
你叫什么名字？
what's your name?
大卫
David.
现在你看到的是非常丑陋的输出
And now you see literally really ugly output,
但你可以从字面上看到发生了什么
but you see literally what's going on.
你好 逗号 空格 然后是三个问号 结束 打印语句
Hello, comma, space, then three question marks, END, that print statement,
然后你会看到D-A-V-I-D 所以这不是个好结果
and then you see D-A-V-I-D. So not a good outcome,
但它也表明了我们在这里也有多大的控制权
but it demonstrates just how much control we have here too.
让我倒得更远一些
And let me rewind further.
回想一下 在我们的另一个版本中
Recall that in our other version of this,
当我传入Hello、逗号和名字时 它们之间用一个空格隔开
when I passed in Hello, comma and name, they were separated by a single space.
所以 在Hello.py的Python中 D-A-V-I-D 回车
So Python of Hello.py, D-A-V-I-D, Enter.
这招真的奏效了
That just worked.
那么 如果我们覆盖分隔符的SEP值 会怎么样？
Well what if we override the value of SEP for separator?
与其成为一个空间 我们可以说些什么
Instead of being one space, we could say something
就像 问号只是为了包装
like, question mark, question mark, question mark just to wrap
我们的脑子里想着那里正在发生的事情
our minds around what's going on there.
现在让我执行Hello.py的Python D-A-V-I-D 回车
Let me now do Python of Hello.py, D-A-V-I-D, Enter.
你会看到两个
And you see two.
这两个输入--
These two inputs--
你好 逗号和名字现在以一种难看的方式分隔
Hello, comma and the name are now separated in an ugly way
三个问号 因为我已经覆盖了SEP的默认行为
by three question marks because I've overridden the default behavior of SEP.
即使文档使用了单引号
And even though the documentation uses single quotes,
我一直有使用双引号的习惯
I've been in the habit of using double quotes.
在Python中 您可以使用其中任何一个
In Python you can use either.
严格地说 这并不重要 但你应该始终如一
Strictly speaking, it doesn't matter, but you should be consistent
而且我通常都会用双引号
and I generally always use double quotes.
不过 Python的文档总是使用单引号
Python's documentation, though, always uses single quotes.
现在有关于这些参数类型的问题吗？
Questions now on these types of parameters?
请允许我提议我们给这些人一个正式的名字
And allow me to propose that we give these an official name.
到目前为止 当我们将值传递给印刷品时
Up until now, when we've been passing values to print,
这些被称为位置参数--在某种意义上是位置参数
those are called positional parameters-- positional in the sense
你传递给Print的第一件东西首先被打印出来
that the first thing you pass to print gets printed first.
在第二次打印逗号之后传递到打印的第二件事
The second thing you pass to print after a comma gets printed second.
以此类推
And so forth.
但我们现在看到的还有一些称为命名参数的东西
But there's also these things we've now seen called named parameters.
命名为SEP、分隔符或结束 E-N-D表示行结束
Named SEP, separator, or END, E-N-D for the line ending.
这些都是命名参数 因为第一 它们是可选的
Those are named parameters because one, they're optional
您可以在打印语句的末尾传递它们
and you can pass them in at the end of your print statement,
但您也可以按名称使用它们
but you can also use them by name.
观众：这可能是一个奇怪的问题 但我想知道
AUDIENCE: This may be a weird question, but I was wondering,
如果有人想要在引语中添加实际的引号怎么办
what if someone wants to add actually quotation marks within the quotation
马克？
marks?
大卫·马兰：是的 我喜欢你的想法
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, I like how you think.
这就是我们所说的角落案例 对吗？
This is what we would call a corner case, right?
就在我们做完--对 这就是全部
Just when we've made-- right, this is all
听起来很棒 至少在编程方面是这样 但是 等一下
sounding great, at least as programming goes, but, wait a minute,
如果您想打印报价 该怎么办？
what if you want to print a quote?
这是一个非常好的问题
That's a really good question.
好吧 让我们看看我们是不是不能解决这个问题
Well, let's see if we can't figure this out.
假设我想打印的不仅仅是用户名
Suppose that I want to print out not just the user's name.
让我进一步简化这一点
Let me simplify this further.
让我继续下去 把很多东西都处理掉
Let me go ahead and get rid of a lot of this,
让我说几句 你好--
and let me just say something like, Hello--
也许我说的有点讽刺了
maybe I'm being a little sarcastic here.
你好 (讽刺地)“朋友”
Hello, (sarcastically) "friend."
你知道 用那种语气
You know, in that kind of tone.
实际上 这是行不通的
Well this is not going to work, actually,
因为你试图用引号在手指引号中表现出“朋友”的形象
because you are trying to use quotes to be like "friend" in finger quotes,
但你也在试图结束这一判决
but you're also trying to end the sentence.
如果我试着运行它 我们就这么做
And if I try running this, let's do this.
您将看到这只是无效的语法
Python of Hello.py, you'll see that this is just invalid syntax.
也许你忘了一个逗号
Perhaps you forgot a comma.
这实际上有点烦人
And this is actually a bit annoying.
有时 您看到的错误消息具有误导性
Sometimes the error messages you see are misleading.
就像电脑 语言 并不是真的
Like the computer, the language, doesn't really
知道发生了什么 所以它会尽最大努力
know what's going on so it gives its best
猜测 但这不一定是正确的
guess, but it's not necessarily correct.
但我可以用几种方法来解决这个问题
But I can solve this problem in a couple of ways.
我能做到的
I can do this--
我可以将最外面的引号更改为单引号
I can change my outermost quotes to single quotes.
因为再次回想起那一刻 我说你
Because recall a moment again, I said you
可以使用双引号或单引号 只要您是一致的
could use double quotes or single quotes so long as you're consistent.
所以这很好
So that's fine.
如果您在外部使用单引号 您将
If you use single quotes on the outside, you
然后可以在内部使用双引号 您将从字面上看到它们
can then use double quotes on the inside and you'll see them literally.
例如 如果我运行Hello.py的Python 我们就可以开始了
So for instance, if I run Python of Hello.py, there we go.
你好 “朋友”
Hello, "friend."
但还有另一种方法
But there's another way.
如果您坚持使用双引号 就像您想要的那样
If you insist on using double quotes as you might want to,
为了保持一致 您还可以再次使用该反斜杠字符
just to be consistent, you can also use that backslash character again.
我们刚才看到了那辆车
We saw the /n a moment ago.
这意味着我们不想让文字n出现在输出中
And that meant we don't want a literal n to be in the output,
我们想要一个新的产品线
we wanted a new line.
因此 反斜杠实际上代表了所谓的转义字符
So the backslash actually represents what's called an escape character.
转义字符是一个你不能仅仅
An escape character is one that you can't just
一定要在键盘上打字一次
type necessarily once on your keyboard.
你需要用多个字符来表达它
You need to express it with multiple characters.
所以我可以在这些内部双引号前面加反斜杠
So I can actually put backslashes in front of these inner double quotes
所以计算机意识到 哦 等一下
so that the computer realizes, Oh wait a minute,
这些不是结束或开始思想的引语 而是字面上的引语
those aren't quotes that finish or start the thought, they're literal quotes.
现在让我返回到我的终端窗口 运行Hello.py的Python 回车
So now let me go back to my terminal window, run Python of Hello.py, Enter.
现在 它也在发挥作用
And now it's working as well.
因此 逃脱是一种通用的技术 它也允许我们这样做
So escaping is a general technique that allows us to do that too.
如果可以的话 现在让我回顾一下这些例子
And if I may, let me rewind now on these examples
然后回到我们停止的地方 用我的代码
and go back to where we left off with my code,
我只是想撤销这一切 因为我想回到正题
I'm just undoing all of that, because I want to get back to the point
最终确定了解决这一问题的最终方法
ultimately of specifying now a final way of solving this problem.
好吧 事实证明我们还有另一种方法
Well, it turns out that we have yet another way
我们可以解决这个问题 这可能是最常做的事情
we can solve this problem, which is perhaps the most frequently done
现在 或者至少是在设置我们的时候最优雅的
now or at least the most elegant when it comes to setting us up
字符串的使用时间越来越长
for longer and longer uses of strings.
您可以使用一个相对较新的Python特性来实现这一点
You can use a relatively new feature of Python that allows you to do this.
您可以直接在字符串中放入变量的名称 而不是这样
You can literally put, not the name of the variable like that in your string,
因为我们已经看到这是错的 对吗？
because we already saw this is wrong, right?
如果您这样做 您将看到您好 逗号 名字
If you do this, you will literally see Hello, comma, name.
但如果我这么做了呢？
But what if I do this?
如果我用花括号或花括号将变量名括起来 会怎么样？
What if I put curly braces or curly brackets around the variable's name?
注意VS Code实际上非常微妙地改变了它的颜色
Notice VS Code is actually very subtly changing the color of it.
所以VS Code知道这里发生了一些有趣的事情
So VS Code knows something interesting is going on here.
让我运行这个程序 但是我还没有运行完
Let me run this program, but I'm not done yet Python of Hello.py, Enter.
D-A-V-I-D 回车
D-A-V-I-D, Enter.
好吧 显然不是我想要的 但我需要告诉Python
OK, obviously not what I want, but I need to tell Python
这是一根特殊的弦
that this is a special string.
这就是我们所说的格式字符串或F字符串
This is what we're going to call a format string or an F string,
在过去的几年中 一种相对较新的特性
a relatively new feature of Python in the past few years
这告诉Python实际上以一种特殊的方式格式化字符串中的内容
that tells Python to actually format stuff in the string in a special way.
从你所做的事情来看 这个符号有点奇怪
And the symbol via what you do this is a little weird,
但这是世界的选择
but this is what the world chose.
如果你把F放在字符串的开头
If you put an F at the beginning of the string,
就在第一个引号之前 这是一个关于Python的线索 哦
right before the first quote mark, that's a clue to Python that, ooh,
这是一根特殊的线
this is a special string.
让我以一种特殊的方式为您格式化
Let me format this in a special way for you.
现在让我重新运行程序
Let me now rerun the program.
Python Hello.py 回车
Python Hello.py, Enter.
D-A-V-I-D 回车
D-A-V-I-D, Enter.
现在我们看到整个过程中的目标--
And now we see the goal this whole time--
你好 大卫
Hello, David.
我们不是以这种方式开始的 因为我认为如果我们以第一种方式进行
We don't start with this way, because I think if we did this the first way,
你会想 我们为什么要这么做？
you'd be like, why are we doing this?
这些神奇的符号是什么？
What are all these magical symbols?
但这只是解决同样问题的另一种方式
But this is just yet another way to solve the same problem.
但让我提议我们现在就考虑
But let me propose that we consider now yet
我们可以用弦做的其他事情
other things we can do with strings.
事实证明 即使我们一直在做一些相对简单的操作
And it turns out that even as we've been doing some relatively simple operations
在这里 我们通常一直相信用户会合作
here, we've generally been trusting that the user is going to cooperate
这就是说 他们实际上会输入我们想要的内容
and that is to say that they're going to actually type in what we want them
打字
to type.
然而 仅仅因为他们输入一个字符串并不意味着
Now just because they type a string, though, doesn't mean
它看起来会像我们想要的那样
it's going to look the way we want.
你和我 老实说 因为人类实际上
You and I, honestly, as humans are actually
在网站和应用程序上 喜欢不小心点击
in the habit-- on websites and apps-- of like accidentally hitting
空格键很多 无论是在我们输入的开始
the spacebar a lot, either at the beginning of our input
或者在最后 可能是因为空格键往往太大了
or at the end, maybe because the space bar tends to be so big.
意外的车位是很常见的
It's pretty common to get accidental spaces
在一些用户输入之前或之后
before or after some users' input.
你和我肯定有不一定要大写单词的习惯
You and I are definitely in the habit of not necessarily capitalizing words
就像我们应该做的那样
like we should.
如果我们在发送短信 我们可能有点快
If we're sending text messages, we're probably being a little quick
把所有东西都用小写字母写出来
and just sending everything in lowercase,
例如 如果这是你的风格 如果你的手机不能为你修复它
for instance, if that's your style, if your phone's not fixing it for you.
也许在一封正式的信中 你会适当地把东西大写
Maybe in a formal letter you would capitalize things properly.
但你和我作为人类 我们不能真的被信任以一种好的方式打字
But you and I as humans, we can't really be trusted to type things in a nice way
在使用某个软件时
necessarily when using some piece of software,
无论是一款应用程序、一个网站还是其他什么
be it an app or a website or something else.
但事实证明 弦本身就是
But it turns out that strings themselves come
具有很多内置功能
with a lot of built-in functionality.
您可以在这里的Python自己的文档中看到所有这些内容
You can see all of that in Python's own documentation here.
我们一直在讨论的字符串数据类型
The string data type that we've been talking about
带有很多内置的功能
comes with a lot of functionality built in that
意味着我们可以操作用户的输入来做更多的事情
means that we can manipulate the user's input to do more than just
加入像Hello这样的东西 我们实际上可以清理它
join it with something else like Hello, we can actually clean it up
或者重新格式化它 希望它看起来对我们更好一点
or reformat it in a way that hopefully looks a little better for us.
所以让我回到我的代码 让我
So let me go back to my code here and let me just
演示如果用户不合作可能会发生的情况
demonstrate what might happen if a user doesn't cooperate.
如果我在这里运行Hello.py的Python 请输入
If I go ahead here and run Python of Hello.py, Enter.
让我草率地按几次空格键
Let me just sloppily hit the spacebar a few too many times.
为什么？
Why?
我只是没有注意到
I just wasn't paying attention.
现在我要输入我的名字D-A-V-I-D 我不知道
And now I'm going to type in my name D-A-V-I-D and, I don't know,
我又按了几次空格键
I hit the spacebar a couple more times.
就像是一团糟
Like it's kind of a mess.
都是小写的
It's all lowercase.
这在语法上看起来不一定是正确的
That's not going to necessarily look grammatically right.
它在这里和这里都有空间
It's got spaces here and here.
程序将打印完全相同的内容
The program is going to print exactly that
这看起来真的很糟糕 至少如果我们
and that looks really bad, at least if we're
优先考虑美学和语法
prioritizing aesthetics and grammar.
比如 为什么逗号后面有这么多空格？
Like, why are there so many spaces after the comma?
这不是一种很好的问候用户的方式
This is not a very nice way to greet your users.
但我们可以把这件事清理干净
But we can clean this up.
结果是内置到字符串中 同样是这种数据类型 所以
It turns out that built into strings, which, again, is this data type, so
可以说 这种类型的数据在Python中--
to speak, this type of data in Python--
是对该字符串进行实际操作的能力
is the ability to actually do things to that string.
所以让我这样做 我可以继续做这样的事情--
So let me do this, I can actually go ahead and do something like this--
名称=名称.条带
name = name.strip.
这是做什么用的？
And what does this do?
从字符串中删除空格
Remove white space from string.
我这么说是什么意思？
And what do I mean by this?
在右手边 请注意我已经
Well, on the right-hand side, notice I've
写入了名为NAME的变量名
written the variable name called Name.
然后我使用句点或点 然后我
I've then used a period or a dot, and then I
似乎在做什么是一个函数 对吗？
seem to be doing what's a function, right?
到目前为止 每当我们看到一个函数时 我们都会看到该函数的名称--print
Any time we've seen a function thus far, we see the function's name-- print
或输入 然后我们看到一个括号 然后是另一个括号
or input, then we see a parenthesis, then another parenthesis,
这正是我在这里看到的
and that's exactly what I see here.
但我使用这个函数的方式略有不同
But I'm using this function a little differently.
从技术上讲 这个函数在本文中称为方法
Technically, this function is-- in this context-- called a method.
我这么说是什么意思？
And what do I mean by that?
嗯 如果名字是一个字符串 又名
Well, if Name is a string, a.k.a.
Str 根据文件 事实证明
STR, well it turns out, according to the documentation,
在Python中有很多与字符串一起提供的函数
there's a lot of functions that come with strings in Python.
您可以通过使用以下命令访问该功能
And you can access that functionality by using
字符串的名称 就像这里的字面意思名称 然后是句点 然后是名称
the name of a string like literally name here, then a period, then the name
函数 然后是一个左括号和一个右括号
of the, function and then an open parenthesis and a closed parenthesis.
可能是圆括号里的一些论点 但在这种情况下
Maybe some arguments inside of those parentheses, but in this case,
它不需要任何争论
it doesn't need any arguments.
我只想剥离左边的空间和空间
I just want to strip the space from the left and the space
从用户输入的右侧
from the right of the user's input.
但这还不够
But that's not enough.
我想要记住 我已经脱下了
I want to remember that I've stripped off
左边和右边的空白处
that white space on the left and the right,
所以我将在这里再次使用等号
so I'm going to use the equal sign again here.
请注意 就像以前一样 这并不意味着平等
And notice that just as before, this doesn't mean equality,
这意味着从右到左进行分配
this means assignment from right to left.
所以当这里的这行代码--名称.条带--
So when this line of code here-- name.strip--
回到我身边 也就是
returns to me, a.k.a.
一个返回值 它将返回相同的东西
a return value, it will return the same thing
用户键入 但左侧不再有空格
that the user typed in, but with no more white space to the left
或者是白色的[咯咯地笑]在右边
or to the white [CHUCKLES] to the right.
所以等号赋值是这样的
So then the equal sign assignment is going
要将该值从右侧复制到左侧
to copy that value from the right to the left,
从而更新My Name变量中的值
thereby updating the value inside of my name variable.
所以你不仅可以给变量赋值
So you can not only assign values to variables,
你完全可以改变变量的值
you can absolutely change the value of variables
通过使用赋值运算符 再次使用等号
by just using the assignment operator, the equal sign again,
一次又一次 它会一直从右边复制
and again, and again, and it will just keep copying from right
不管新值应该是多少
to left whatever the new value should be.
所以现在如果我运行这个程序 Hello.py的Python 回车
So now if I rerun this program, Python of Hello.py, Enter.
我有D-A-V-I--噢 我们再来一次
I have D-A-V-I-- oop, let's do it again.
空间 空间 d-a-v-i-d在所有的空间中
Space, space, space, space, space. d-a-v-i-d in all lowercase, space,
空格 回车
space, Enter.
好多了
It's better.
它还没有固定我的资本化 所以我仍然
It hasn't fixed my capitalization, so I'm still
第一个D有点马虎 但它已经剥离了
being a little sloppy with the first D, But it has stripped off
所有这些额外的空间
all of that extra space.
很小的细节 对吧？
Super minor detail, right?
好像这并不那么令人兴奋 但是
Like this isn't all that exciting, but it just
这说明了你只用一行代码就能做什么
speaks to the power of what you can do with just a single line of code.
我还能做什么
Now what else can I do here?
我可以把用户输入的信息大写
Well I could capitalize the user's input.
我来试试这个
Let me go ahead and try this.
我也可以这样做--name. capitalize
It turns out that I could also do this-- name.capitalize.
所以让我把用户名大写
So let me go ahead and capitalize user's name.
再一次 我发表评论
And again, I'm making comments and there's
没有一个正确的方式来写评论
no one right way to write the comments.
我只是在这里用一些简短的英语短语
I'm just using some short English phrases here
提醒自己我在做什么
to remind myself of what I'm doing.
这是怎么回事
What's now going on here?
让我继续运行Hello.py的Python 回车
Well let me go ahead and run Python of Hello.py, Enter.
空间 d-a-v-i-d 空间 空间 输入
Space, space, space, space, space, d-a-v-i-d, space, space, Enter.
好的.
OK.
现在看起来更漂亮了 对吧？
Now it's looking prettier, right?
无论用户如何输入他们的名字 即使有点草率
No matter how the user typed in their name, even a little sloppily,
我正在修正
I'm now fixing that.
但让我们试试别的
But let's try something.
我有点好奇了
I'm getting a little curious here.
这个怎么样？
How about this?
空间 d-a-v-i-d空间m-a-l-a-n--
Space, space, space, space, space, d-a-v-i-d space m-a-l-a-n--
我现在用我的姓
I'll use my last name now--
输入.
Enter.
好吧 讽刺的是 “资本化”并不是真正的资本化我们想要的一切
OK, so ironically, "capitalize" is not really capitalizing everything we want.
很明显资本化了什么？
It's clearly capitalizing what?
只有第一封信
Just the very first letter.
结果是 Python中还有其他函数
So it turns out that, again, there's other functions in Python
有附带条件的
that come with strings.
如果我们浏览文档 滚动浏览这样的URL
And if we poke around the documentation, scrolling through a URL like that,
我打赌我们会找到另一个解决方案 其中一个实际上就是这个
I bet we'll find another solution, one of which is actually this.
让我们将其实际更改为标题
Let's actually change this to title.
还有另一个函数与字符串一起提供
There's yet another function that comes with strings
被称为基于标题大写的标题 只是
called Title that do title-based capitalization, just
像一本书或一个人的名字 大写
like a book or a person's name, capitalizing
每个单词的第一个字母
the first letter of each word.
这将为我们做更多的工作
And this is just going to do a little more work for us.
所以让我们继续运行这个
So let's go ahead and run this.
顺便说一句 我现在有点累了
And as an aside, I'm kind of tired now at this point
一直在打字 一直在打字
of typing Python, Python, Python all the time.
事实证明 当使用这样的命令行界面时
It turns out that when using a command line interface like this,
实际上 您可以重新执行所有旧命令
you can actually go back through all of your old commands.
我刚才所做的就是我点击了向上箭头
What I just did a moment ago was I hit the up arrow.
这会立即回顾我所有命令的历史记录
That immediately goes back through my history of all of the commands
我打字最多的一次
I've ever typed.
所以这是一种更快的方式让我再重复一遍
So this is just a faster way now for me to repeat myself
而不是手动输入所有内容
than typing everything manually.
让我继续按Enter 空格键 空格键
Let me go ahead and hit Enter, space, space, space, space, space,
D-a-v-i-d m-a-L-a-n空格 空格 全部小写 回车
d-a-v-i-d m-a-l-a-n space, space, all lowercase, Enter.
现在它看起来好多了
Now it's looking better.
现在我把东西都大写了 把东西都清理干净了
Now I've capitalized things and cleaned things up.
但是我的代码呢？
But what about my code?
我现在有八行代码 其中四行
I've got like eight lines of code now, four of which
是注释 其中四个是实际代码
are comments, four of which are actual code.
我真的需要这么多吗？
Do I really need this much?
嗯 不一定
Well, not necessarily.
看看我还能用Python语言做什么
Watch what I can also do in Python.
让我不必费心将用户名单独大写
Let me not bother capitalizing the user's name separately.
让我这么说吧--
Let me say this--
并将用户名大写
and capitalize user's name.
我可以将这些功能链接在一起
I can chain these functions together.
我可以在这篇文章的末尾加上标题
I can add Title to the end of this.
现在又是怎么回事？
And now what's happening?
再说一次 有这样一行代码
Well again, with a line of code like this,
你首先把注意力放在等号的右边
you first focus on what's to the right of the equal sign,
然后我们就到等号的左边
then we'll get to the left of the equal sign.
等号的右边是什么？
What's on the right of the equals sign?
这条线在这里
This line here.
这是什么意思？
Well what does this mean?
获取名称变量的值 如D-A-V-I-D空格M-A-L-A-N
Get the value of the name variable, like D-A-V-I-D space, M-A-L-A-N.
然后去掉左右两边的空白处
Then strip off the white space on the left and the right.
这将返回一个值
That is going to return a value.
它将返回D-A-V-I-D空间M-A-L-A-N 不带任何空格
It's going to return D-A-V-I-D space M-A-L-A-N without any white space
向左或向右
to the left or right.
您希望如何处理该返回值？
What do you want to do with that return value?
你想让它的标题大小写 也就是
You want Python to title case it, that is
检查结果字符串中的每个单词
go through every word in that resulting string
并固定第一个单词的第一个字母 第一个字母
and fix the first letter of the first word, the first letter
第二个词 以此类推
of the second word, and so forth.
然后--现在我们可以结束我们的想法了--
And then-- now we can finish our thought--
将整个代码从右向左复制到相同名称的变量中
copy the whole thing from right to left into that same name variable.
你知道吗？
And you know what?
我可以把这件事做得更进一步
I can take this even one step further.
如果我们想的话 我们为什么不继续这样做呢？
Why don't we go ahead and do this if we want.
让我摆脱所有这些 让我只做脱衣舞和标题
Let me get rid of all of that, and let me just do strip and title
都在第一条线上
all on that first line.
现在我们已经从8行代码变成了4行代码
And now we've gone from like eight lines of code to four.
它要紧得多
It's a lot tighter.
这样整洁多了
It's a lot neater.
即使理性的人可能不同意
And even though reasonable people might disagree,
可以说 它更好 因为它更容易阅读
it's arguably better because it's just easier to read.
更少的代码行 更少的出错机会
Fewer lines of code, fewer opportunities for mistakes,
它只会让我继续处理我要解决的下一个问题
it just allows me to move on with my next problem to solve.
好了 让我在这里暂停一下 看看是否有关于这些方法的问题
All right, let me pause here and see if there's any questions on these methods.
方法是内置在一种值类型中的函数
A method is a function that's built in to a type of value,
就像这些函数一样
like these functions are.
或者在我们刚才看到的F弦上
Or on F strings which we saw a moment ago.
观众：是的 嗨
AUDIENCE: Yes, hi.
谢谢你 大卫
Thanks, David.
那么有没有办法去掉空格之间的空格呢？
So is there a way to remove the spaces between the spaces
我可能会加进去的？
that I might have added?
大卫·马兰：简单地说 没有
DAVID MALAN: Short answer, no.
如果您之前阅读了同一URL上的文档
If you read the documentation at that same URL earlier,
您将看到该条带从左侧和右侧移除 但不会从两者之间移除
you'll see that strip removes from the left and the right, but not in between.
事实上 还有另外两个带有字符串的函数
In fact, there's two other functions that come with strings.
一条叫L条 一条叫R条
One is called L strip, the other is called R strip,
这让你可以选择其中之一
that allow you to do one or the other.
如果我们想要开始去除中间的空间
If we want to start getting rid of space in the middle,
我们将不得不玩一个完全不同的把戏
we're going to have to do a different trick altogether.
观众：有多少函数可以像这样组合在一起
AUDIENCE: How many functions can be combine like this dot strip, dot title,
加在一起
all combined.
那么我们可以合并多少个呢？
So how many we can combine?
大卫·马兰：是的 这是一个非常好的问题
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, a really good question.
从技术上讲 你想要多少就有多少 但到了某个时候
Technically, as many as you want, but at some point
你的代码会开始看起来非常非常糟糕 对吗？
your code is going to start to look really, really bad, right?
因为代码行会变得非常非常长
Because the line of code is going to get really, really long.
它最终可能会一次又一次地缠绕在一起
It's eventually going to maybe wrap around again and again.
所以在某种程度上 你只是说 嗯-嗯 太多了
So at some point, you just kind of say like, uh-uh, that's too many.
然后你开始像我一样把它分成多行
And you start breaking it up into multiple lines like I did.
可能会根据需要将值重新赋值给变量
Maybe reassigning the value to the variable as needed.
这实际上是一个很好的问题
And this is actually a good question.
如果我可以绕过你的问题 我是说 人们是怎么想的？
If I can pivot, [INAUDIBLE] off your question, I mean, what do people think?
如果我们能继续把大家的手放下来一会儿
If we could go ahead and put everyone's hands down for a moment.
让我问一下--
Let me ask this--
就是我现在做这件事的方式 用条幅、标题和输入
is the way I've done this now, with strip and title and input
都在同一条线上--
all in the same line--
比我以前的方法更好吗？
better than my previous approach?
在缩放中 您可以使用是图标或否图标
In Zoom you can use the Yes icon or the No icon.
如果你认为这个版本更好 那就说是
If you think this version is better, say Yes.
例如 如果你认为以前的版本更好
If you think this previous version was better, for instance,
在这里 我们所有的事情都爆发了 说不
this one here where we had everything broken out, say No.
稍后我们再来看看原因
And then we'll see why in just a moment.
我早些时候提出 理性的人可以持不同意见
I proposed earlier that reasonable people can disagree
这绝对是事实
and that's absolutely the case.
这样或那样做并不一定是最好的
Doing it one way or the other isn't necessarily best,
至少如果你能证明这一点的话
at least if you can justify it.
让我回到这里的最新版本
Let me go back to the most recent version here.
好的 我们看到了很多赞成者和反对者
All right so we're seeing a lot of Yeses and a lot of Nos.
如果可以的话 我们何不去拜访其中一位赞成者呢？
Why don't we go ahead and call on one of the Yeses, if we could.
投赞成票的人 为什么你认为这段代码的当前版本
Someone who's voting Yes, why do you think the current version of this code
真的比之前更长的代码版本更好吗？
is indeed better than the previous longer version of the code?
观众：我觉得它的可读性更强
AUDIENCE: I think it's more readable.
所以我可以说 这就是名称变量
So I can say, this is the name variable.
它得到一些输入 然后删除空格并给它一个标题
It gets some input and then remove the space and give it a title.
这就对了
And there you go.
你有一个你好 名字
You have a hello, name.
大卫·马兰：是的 我认为这很合理
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, I think that's pretty reasonable.
它的可读性非常好 至少如果你有这个习惯的话
It's very readable, at least if you're in the habit,
就像你在英语里一样 从左到右阅读
as you are in English, of reading left to right.
结果 它就像是一种非常自然的流动
It just kind of flows very naturally as a result.
队伍并不是真的那么长
The lines is not really that long.
当然 它非常适合屏幕
It's certainly fitting nicely onto the screen.
所以我认为这是一个很好的论点
So I think that's a good argument.
不过 找个对立面怎么样？
How about a counterpoint, though?
投反对票的人 如果我们可以呼吁一个认为情况更糟的人
Someone who voted No, if we could call on someone who thinks this is worse.
观众：因为它根本读不懂
AUDIENCE: Because it's not readable at all.
好像排了很长的队
It seems like it's a very long line.
所以我觉得还是分开比较好
So I think it's better to separate.
大卫·马兰：是的
DAVID MALAN: Yeah.
我觉得这也很有说服力 对吧？
I think that's persuasive too, right?
它变得更长了一点
It's getting a little longer.
尽管我在这里的句子--你的名字--相对较短
And even though my sentence here-- what's your name-- is relatively short,
你可以想象 这可能会很快变得更加丑陋
you could imagine that this could get even uglier quickly
如果我问用户一个更长的问题 那就是
if I were asking a longer question of the user, that's
这会使这行代码更长 因此可读性更差
going to make this line of code even longer and therefore less readable.
对于我或我的同事来说 我可能不太清楚我正在打电话给Stand
It might be less obvious to me or my colleagues that I am calling strip
也不知道我在叫什么头衔
or that I am calling title.
这可能是一种意想不到的惊喜
It might be kind of an unexpected surprise.
所以我认为这也是合理的
So I think that's reasonable too.
简而言之 这里没有正确的答案
In short, there is no right answer here.
事实上 提高编程水平的过程的一部分
And in fact, part of the process of getting better at programming
是获得自己的风格 还是为一家公司工作
is getting your own sense of style or working for a company
在那里他们可能会指定哪种方法比另一种方法更好
where they might prescribe which way is better than the other
因为他们只是想让每个人都做同样的事情
because they just want everyone doing the same thing,
即使通情达理的人可能不同意
even though reasonable people might disagree.
不过 最终 只要你拥有
Ultimately though, so long as you have what's
支持一种或另一种方式的一个相当好的论点 比如最终
a pretty good argument in favor of one way or the other, like ultimately,
这才是最重要的
that's what's important.
如果你只是因为你真的不知道哪一个更好而做事情
If you're just doing things because you don't really know which one is better,
这可不是什么好事
that's not great.
但如果你开始收集意见
But if and when you start to acquire opinions
如果你的老板 你的老师 你的同事 你的朋友
and if your boss, if your teacher, if your colleague, your friend,
可以挑战你 说 等等 你为什么要这样做？
can challenge you and say, wait, why did you do it like this?
他们可能不同意你的观点 但至少有一个答案
They might not agree with you, but at least have an answer,
总的来说 这应该是足够有说服力的
and that should be sufficiently persuasive in general.
现在 字符串附带了一大堆其他方法
Now, strings come with a whole bunch of other methods
其中有一种叫做Split 顾名思义 它可以
as well, among which is one called split, which can, as the name suggests,
可以这么说 将一个字符串拆分成多个更小的子字符串
split a string into multiple smaller substrings, so to speak.
例如 如果这里的人有这样的习惯
For instance, if the human here is in the habit
输入他们的名字 然后是一个空格 然后是他们的姓氏
of typing in their first name, then a space, and then their last name,
你只想直接和他们打招呼
and you want to go ahead and greet them only by first name,
我们实际上可以利用这个单一的空间
well we could actually leverage that single space
在名字和姓氏之间 并拆分该字符串
between the first name and last name and split that string
分成两个更小的子串
into two smaller substrings.
我们怎么能做到这一点？
How can we do this?
好吧 让我继续 在这些字里行间
Well, let me go ahead and in between these lines
主动评论我们即将拆分用户的
proactively comment that we're about to split user's
将名字转换为名字和姓氏
name into first name and last name.
然后让我们继续获取这个名称变量 它当前包含
And then let's go ahead and take that name variable, which currently contains
大概是大卫 太空 马兰
something like, presumably, David, space, Malan,
让我继续调用Split并作为参数传入
and let me go ahead and call split and pass in as the argument
分隔单个空格 从而表明我确实
to split a single white space, thereby indicating that I indeed
我想在那个角色上分道扬镳
want to split on that character
现在 Split将返回一个值序列 理想情况下
Now it turns out split is going to return a sequence of values, ideally
先是名 然后是姓
a first name and then a last name.
实际上 在Python中 我们可以为这两个值赋值
And we can actually, in Python, assign both of those values
从这个序列一次转换到一些变量
from that sequence at once to some variables.
例如 第一个逗号最后一个等于 那就是
For instance, first comma last equals, and that's
会产生从右到左的效果
going to have the effect from right to left
将第一个这样的值放入第一个变量 第二个这样的值
of putting the first such value in the first variable, the second such value
在第二个变量中
in the second variable.
现在 在我的最后一行代码中 我可以进去打招呼了
So now on my last line of code, I can go in and say hello
不是全名 比如大卫·马兰
not to the full name, something like David Malan,
我可以先打个招呼
I can just say Hello, first.
好的 让我们继续清除我的终端窗口 运行Hello.py的Python
All right, let's go ahead and clear my terminal window, run Python of Hello.py
然后按Enter键
and hit Enter.
这一次我不会费心使用任何前导空格 但让我继续
I won't bother with any leading white space this time, but let me go ahead
然后输入David空格Malan 像往常一样交叉手指 你好
and type in David space Malan, and crossing my fingers as usual, Hello,
大卫就是我们现在所看到的
David is what we now see.
好的 到目前为止 我们已经看到了很多例子 其中包括
All right, so we've seen so much, so many examples thus far involving
字符串 但程序和编程语言肯定可以
strings, but certainly programs and programming languages can
也可以操纵其他类型的数据
manipulate other types of data as well.
让我们继续 然后转换到另一种非常常见的数据类型
Let's go ahead and transition then to another very common type of data
在Python语言中 在更一般的编程中 即
in Python, in programming more generally, namely
整数 在Python语言中也称为int--
integers, otherwise known in Python as INT--
I-N-T因此 就像STR一样 S-T-R是字符串的缩写 在Python语言中也是int的缩写
I-N-T. So just as STR, S-T-R is short for string, so is INT in Python
整数的缩写
short for integer.
那么 整数是什么？
Well, what's an integer?
就像在数学中一样 它是一个负2这样的数字
Well just like in math it's a number like negative 2,
负1 0 1 2 一直到负无穷大 全部
negative 1, 0, 1, 2, and all the way toward negative infinity, all
通向正无穷大的道路
the way toward positive infinity.
但是整数里没有小数点
But there's no decimal point in an integer.
它只是一个数字 像负2 负1 0 1和2
It's just a number like negative 2, negative 1, 0, 1, and 2 onward.
这是一个整型
That's an INT.
当然 在数学世界里 我们使用了很多符号
Of course, in the world of mathematics, there's lots of symbols that we use.
我们以前见过+ 尽管我们把它用在了不同的目的上
And we've seen + before, although we used it for a different purpose.
但Python支持这些符号以及更多符号
But Python supports these symbols and more.
而Python允许你把数字加在一起+
And Python allows you to add numbers together +,
减数、乘数、除数
subtract numbers, multiply numbers, divide numbers.
这里唯一一个对人们来说可能有点陌生或陌生的
And the only one here that might look a little strange to people or unfamiliar
这是百分比符号 但在这种情况下 它并不意味着百分比
is this percent sign, but it doesn't mean percent in this context.
如果您在Python程序中使用单个百分号
If you use a single percent sign in a Python program,
这实际上就是所谓的模运算符
that's actually the so-called modulo operator,
允许您在除法后取余数的运算符
the operator that allows you to take the remainder after dividing
一个数字接一个数字
one number by another.
我们很快就会看到这样的例子 但前四个例子
So we'll see examples of that before long, but the first four of these
可能是非常非常熟悉的
are perhaps quite, quite familiar.
事实证明 在Python中 你不一定--
Well it turns out that in Python you cannot necessarily--
您不必一直在像Hello.py这样的文件中编写代码
you don't necessarily have to keep writing code in a file like Hello.py
然后在终端窗口中运行它
and then running it in a terminal window.
许多人喜欢的关于Python的功能之一
One of the features that many people like about Python
就是它支持这种所谓的互动模式
is that it supports this so-called interactive mode.
就像您可以开始编写Python代码并立即执行
Like you can start writing Python code and immediately execute
其中的每一行都是交互的 尤其是
each of those lines interactively, especially
如果您不关心保存所有代码行的话
if you don't care about saving all of your lines of code.
您只想执行代码并返回一些答案
You just want to execute code and get back some answers.
例如 让我回到这里的VS代码 并关闭Hello.py
So for instance, let me go back to VS Code here and let me close Hello.py
让我点击终端窗口中的小三角形
and let me click on the little triangle over here in my terminal window just
让它变得更大 只是暂时的
to make it much bigger just temporarily for a moment.
因此 我现在不会创建任何.py文件 我只会单独运行Python
So I'm not creating any .py file now, I'm just going to run Python by itself
在我的提示下
at my prompt.
你们会看到 当我这样做的时候 我得到了一些看起来很神秘的输出
And you'll see when I do this, I get some cryptic looking output
以及程序最后更新的日期和时间等
and the date and time at which the program was last updated, and so forth.
但我最终得到了三个像这样的三重括号
But I ultimately get three triple brackets like this.
是Python的交互模式
Is the interactive mode for Python.
所以我运行的是Python解释器 任何时候我输入一行代码
So I'm running the Python interpreter and any time I type a line of code
在解释器中 它将立即执行它
in the interpreter, it's going to execute it immediately.
我不必一次又一次地运行Python
I don't have to keep running Python again and again.
这就好像在人类世界里 如果你
It's as though in the human world, if you
站在一个会说其他语言的人旁边
were standing next to a human who speaks some other language,
而你只是在和他们来回交谈
and you're just having a conversation with them back and forth,
这一切都发生了--翻译过来--立刻
it's all happening-- the translation-- immediately.
那么 在交互模式下我可以做什么呢？
So what might I do in interactive mode?
嗯 我可以做一些类似1+1的动作 进入
Well I could do something like 1 + 1, Enter.
那其实是暗号 好吗？
That's actually code, all right?
您可能不会认为它是代码 但如果有一点算术和您的
You might not think of it as code, but if a bit of arithmetic and you
知道数字 你知道+ 这是有效的Python代码
know numbers, and you know +, that's valid Python code.
你可以把Python当做一个奇特的计算器来使用
And you can use Python really as a fancy calculator.
但我也可以做其他的事情
But I could do other things too.
如果我想打印给我自己你好 世界
If I want to print to myself Hello, world,
我也可以在那里打印出那一行代码--
I can also print out that line of code there too--
你好 世界
Hello, world.
所以它是互动的 从这个意义上说
So it's interactive in the sense that the moment
你执行一行代码 砰的一声 你就会看到结果
you execute a line of code, boom, you see the result.
我们通常不会这样做 因为至少当
We're generally not going to do that because at least when
教授语言时 我们倾向于循序渐进地做事情
teaching the language, we tend to want to do things incrementally
我们希望你们能够看到我们来自哪里
and we want you to be able to see where it is we came from.
我们希望能够一次又一次地尝试 特别是
And we want to be able to try things again and again, especially
如果我们犯了错误
if we make mistakes.
但要知道 这确实是Python的一个功能
But know that this is indeed a feature of Python,
这种所谓的互动模式
this so-called interactive mode.
但现在让我们关注一下 不仅仅是这种互动
But let's focus for a moment now, not just on that interactivity,
但真正基于这样一个事实 Python显然
but really on the fact that Python apparently
支持整数、数学和其中一些基本运算
supports integers and mathematics and some of those basic operations.
让我们看看我们是不是不能做我们自己的小计算器
And let's see if we can't make maybe our own little calculator.
所以让我继续 再次打开VS代码
So let me go ahead and open up VS Code again,
我要缩小我的终端窗口
and I'm going to shrink down my terminal window,
我将创建一个名为Calculator.py的新文件
and I'm going to create a new file called Calculator.py.
因此 要进行回调 我可以在下面输入Code
So to do that recall, I can type Code down here,
和我想要创建的文件的名称.py 输入
and the name of the file I want to create, .py, Enter.
这给了我一个新的顶端标签
That gives me a new tab up top.
所以我已经关闭了Hello.py
So I have already closed Hello.py.
我现在在Calculator.py中
I'm now in Calculator.py.
让我们做一个简单的计算器 为我做一些加法
And let's just make a simple calculator that does some addition for me.
但我将在一个文件中这样做 这样我们就可以对此进行迭代
But I'm going to do it in a file so that we can iterate on this
并随着时间的推移做出改变 无论是好是坏
and make changes for better or for worse over time.
让我继续 首先声明几个变量
Let me go ahead and first declare a couple of variables.
我要做一个数学运算 把我的第一个变量命名为x
I'm going to do the mathematical thing of calling my first variable x,
我的第二个变量y 然后我要给自己
my second variable y, and then I'm going to give myself
第三个变量z=x+y
a third variable z = x + y.
然后我将继续打印z
And then I'm going to go ahead and print out z.
现在这个节目 诚然不是很令人兴奋或有趣
Now this program, admittedly not very exciting or interesting,
事实上 它没有在屏幕上打印东西那么有趣
in fact, it's a little less interesting than printing stuff on the screen
就像以前使用字符串一样 但我们将在此基础上进行构建
like before with strings, but we'll build on this
看看我们还可以利用在Python中的哪些其他特性
and see what other features exist in Python that we can leverage.
所以希望 如果Python像我一样知道这是数学问题
So hopefully, if Python knows it's math as well as I do,
当我运行Calculator.py的Python时 我应该希望看到1+2
when I run Python of Calculator.py, I should see hopefully that 1 + 2
=确实是3
= indeed 3.
好吧 所以并不令人惊讶 也不是那么有趣
All right, so not that surprising and not that interesting.
老实说 这不是最有用的程序
And honestly this isn't the most useful program
因为它总是要计算1+2=3
because it's always going to calculate 1 + 2 = 3.
让我们至少让这个节目 比如说 更具互动性 对吗？
Let's at least make this program, say, a little more interactive, right?
我们已经从前面的例子中知道了如何从用户那里获得输入
We already know from previous examples how we can get input from the user.
让我们恢复输入函数
Let's bring back that input function.
让我们这样做 让我现在继续 在我的代码的顶部
And let's do this, let me go ahead now and at the top of my code,
让我们将x更改为不总是数字1
let's change x to not be the number 1 always,
让我们把它改成任何回报
let's change it to be whatever the return
价值在于向用户索要x
value is of asking the user for x.
我可以在这里使用任何我想要的英语或人类语言
And I can use any English or human language I want here.
我要说 x是什么？
I'm going to say, what's x?
就像我之前问的 你叫什么名字？
Just like I asked before, what's your name?
我也会为y做同样的事情
And I'm going to do the same thing for y.
我将再次使用输入 但这一次将问题改为
I'm going to use Input again, but this time change the question to be,
你是什么？
what's y?
好了 在这一点上 我想我将把剩下的代码
All right, at this point, I think I'm going to leave the rest of the code
一样的
the same.
Z=x+y 然后打印z 但什么是好的
Z = x + y And then print z but what's nice
现在我想我有了一个很好的交互式计算器
now is that I think I have a nice interactive calculator.
好的 现在它不会一直做1+2
Right, now it's not going to do 1 + 2 all the time.
它将执行用户输入的任何内容+用户输入的任何内容
It's going to do whatever the user types + whatever the user types.
那么让我们来试试这个
So let's try this.
让我继续运行这个程序
Let me go ahead and run that program.
好了 我们开始吧
All right, let's do it.
1将是x 2将是y 当然 所有同意的人 1
1 is going to be x, 2 is going to be y, and of course, everyone in agreement, 1
+2=Thr--
+ 2 = thr--
哈
huh.
那是怎么回事？
What's going on there?
不是你的数学课误导了你 就是我误导了你
Either your math class misled you or I have misled you.
我们为什么不叫个人来看看你是否
Why don't we call on someone here to see if you
不能帮助我们推断错误是什么 错误在哪里？
can't help us reason through what the bug is, what's the mistake?
安加利 如果我没说错的话
Anjali, if I'm saying it right.
观众：我认为问题在于它连接了字符串 因为你
AUDIENCE: I think the issue is that it's concatenating strings because you
使用+运算符 而不是加法
use the + operator instead of adding.
大卫·马兰：太好了
DAVID MALAN: Perfect.
如此完美的直觉
So perfect intuition.
我们已经看到+在字符串上下文中的用法略有不同
We've seen that + is used a little differently in the context of strings
因为它连接 也就是连接两个字符串
because it concatenates, that is, it joins the two strings,
这似乎确实是这里正在发生的事情
and that seems to Indeed be what's happening here,
即使用户输入了数字
even though the user typed a number.
但有趣的是
But the interesting thing here is that, when
你得到用户输入 因为他们在Mac上使用键盘
you get user input, because they're using a keyboard on their Mac
或者电脑或者手机 都是短信
or PC or their phone, it is always going to be text.
它可能看起来像一个数字 但默认情况下
It might look like a number, but by default,
从键盘上传来的字符串
it's coming from the keyboard as a string--
即作为文本
that is, as text.
那么 如果我们最终
And so, how do we go about resolving this if ultimately we
我不想把这些输入当作字符串
don't want to treat those inputs as strings,
我们要把它们当作真实的数字吗
we want to treat them as actual numbers?
我们需要另一个函数 在Python中
Well we need another function and it turns out in Python
有时候你可以把一种数据转换成另一种数据
that you can convert sometimes from one type of data to another type of data,
例如 从字符串到INT 通过这样做
for instance, from string to INT by doing something like this.
让我回到我的代码 让我改变
Let me go back into my code and let me change
在把它加到y之前
x before adding it to y to be whatever the integer version of x
是 +不管y的整数形式是什么
is, + whatever the integer version of y is.
因此 INT不仅是Python中的一种数据类型
So it turns out that INT is not only a type of data in Python,
它也是一个函数
it's also a function, and it's a function
如果你传入一个输入 比如一个字符串
that if you pass in an input, like a string,
只要这个字符串看起来像1或2这样的数字
so long as that string looks like a number like 1 or like 2,
它会把它转换成一个实际的数字
it will convert it to an actual number that you can perform mathematics
而不是
on instead.
如果我现在回到终端窗口运行Python
So if I now go back to my terminal window and run Python--
我再给你看一个小把戏
and let me show you another trick.
“计算器”这个词有点长
"Calculator" is kind of a long word.
打字有点乏味
It's a little tedious to type.
注意我可以在终端窗口的命令行中做什么
Notice what I can do in my terminal window, in a command line
接口一般
interface in general.
如果我开始输入C-A-L作为计算器
If I start typing C-A-L for calculator, I can actually
按Tab完成我的想法
hit Tab to finish my thought.
所以在这样的终端窗口中自动完成是可能的
So auto-complete is possible in a terminal window like this.
输入第一个字母或几个字母 然后 砰 与标签
Type the first letter or few letters and then, boom, with Tab,
它会帮你完成你的想法
it'll finish your thought for you.
或者你可以像我用上下箭头那样回到你的历史中
Or you can go back in your history like I did with the Up and Down Arrows.
让我继续执行这个
Let me go ahead and execute this.
什么是X？
What's x?
1.
什么是X？
What's x?
2.
好了
And there we go.
现在我们有了一个通用计算器
Now we have a general purpose calculator that's going to support
不只是1和2的加法 而是任意两个
not just the addition of 1 and 2, but now any two
用户键入的整数
integers that the user types.
现在让我来改进一下 好吗？
And let me now improve this, right?
我们已经了解了如何改进代码
We've seen how we can make improvements to code
我不知道这是否一定会更好
and I don't know if it's going to necessarily be better,
但让我们来试试这个
but let's try this.
我真的需要z变量吗？
Do I really need the z variable?
值得注意的是 我正在创建一个名为z的变量
It's worth noting that I'm creating a variable called z,
然后我立即在下一行代码中使用它
and then I'm immediately using it on the next line of code.
这并不是很有说服力 因为如果你要创建一个变量
Now that's not that compelling, because if you're creating a variable
然后立即使用它 但永远不会再使用它
and then immediately using it, but never again using it,
你真的需要花时间介绍另一个符号吗？
did you really need to take the time to introduce another symbol
和另一个变量 只使用一次 只使用一次？
and another variable just to use it once and only once?
嗯 也许不是
Well, maybe not.
也许我们在这种情况下并不真正需要z
Maybe we don't really need z in this way.
也许我应该去做一些这样的事情
Maybe I should go and do something like this.
也许我应该在这里除掉z
Maybe I should get rid of z here.
也许我应该把这个改成INT 换掉
Maybe I should change this to be INT up here, change
这是在这里 做了一些现在很有趣的事情
this to be INT up here, doing something that's pretty interesting now.
尽管这是一种新的语法 但请注意
Even though it's a bit of new syntax, notice that you
可以说 可以嵌套函数
can nest functions, so to speak.
您可以将一个函数调用放入一个函数的使用
You can put one function call that is the use of a function
在内部使用另一个函数 以便返回
inside of the use of another function so that the return
内部函数的值将成为
value of the inner function becomes the argument to
或外部函数的输入
or the input to the outer function.
就像在数学中 如果你有圆括号
Just like in math, if you have parentheses, parentheses, parentheses,
你的老师可能教你要集中注意力
your teacher probably taught you to focus
先看看最里面的圆括号里有什么
on what's inside the innermost parentheses first
然后自己想办法脱身
and then work your way out.
编程也是如此
Same thing with programming.
这就是Python要做的事情
That's what's Python is going to do.
它将首先查看括号内的内容
It's going to look at what's inside of the parentheses first,
它会得到答案 然后它就会
it's going to get the answer, and then it's
将返回值传递给最外层的函数
going to pass the return value to the outermost function.
所以现在在第1行发生的事情是 输入函数首先被调用
So what happens on line 1 now is that the input function gets called first,
然后 结果是 引用不引用的一
then the result of that, quote unquote one
成为int函数的输入 在第2行上也是如此
becomes the input to the INT function, and same on line 2.
Y的输出变成了这个int函数的输入
The output of what's y becomes the input to this INT function.
现在没有z了
And now there is no z.
我可以只打印x+y
I could just do print x + y.
因为我花了时间把每一个字符串
And because I've taken the time to convert each of those strings
到了一个整数 我想我们就可以了
to an integer, I think we're OK.
让我试一试 Calculator.py的Python 回车
So let me try this, Python of Calculator.py, Enter.
1和2 而我们仍然得到3
1 and 2, and we're still getting 3.
不是12 或者不是12 1 2 我们确实得到了3
Not 12, or not 12, 1,2, we're indeed getting 3.
我们还去掉了变量
And we've additionally gotten rid of the variable
因为我们似乎不一定需要它
because we didn't necessarily need it, it seems,
尤其是如果只用一次的话
especially if only using it once.
好吧 在这里也是 让我把每个人的手放下来一会儿
Well here too, let me put everyone's hands down for just a moment
让我一如既往地问--
and let me ask as before--
这个版本现在在输入的调用周围使用int
this version now which uses INT around the invocations of input,
并且没有使用z 这比以前的版本更好吗？
and does not use z, is this better than the previous version?
如果你想投赞成票 那就投赞成票
If you want to vote Yes, go ahead.
或者 如果你更喜欢旧的方式 投反对票
Or if you prefer the old way, vote No.
原来的方式是 我会在投票时取消这一切 而不是像这样
The old way, I'll undo all of this as we vote, instead looked like this.
好的 现在让我回到最新的版本
All right, and let me go back to now the newest version.
让我们握住赞成者的手 这个人
Let's take a hand of the Yeses, someone who
认为这个最新版本更好
thinks this latest version is better.
观众：我认为这种方式更好 因为它可以让我们立即看到
AUDIENCE: I think this way is better because it allows us to immediately see
对于整数 x和y变量是什么
what the x and y variables are with integers
因此 我们知道应该从他们那里得到什么
and so we know what to expect from them.
而且 印刷品的论点也更直观
And also the print argument is more intuitive.
我们避免了代码中的太多混乱
We avoid too much clutter in the code.
大卫·马兰：我认为这些都是很好的理由
DAVID MALAN: I think those are all good reasons.
它很好 也很简洁
It's nice and succinct.
代码行不是很长
The lines of code are not very long.
我不需要知道z是什么 因为它不存在
I don't need to know what z is because it doesn't exist.
它只看到打印x+y
It just sees print x + y.
我喜欢那样
I like that.
但有人更喜欢老式的方式 我们确实有z
But someone who prefers the older way where we did have z
并且我们更显式地将单个变量传递给int函数
and we more explicitly passed individual variables to the INT function.
观众：是的 嗨
AUDIENCE: Yeah, hi.
我认为较早的版本更好 因为当--
I think that the earlier version is better because when--
我的意思是 如果用户输入的内容不是
I mean, if user input something else other than,
比方说 我是说 比方说 他们输入1和2
let's say, I mean, let's say, they type 1 and 2, like,
因此 它将更容易调试
so it will be easier to debug.
大卫·马兰：这个版本还是--这里的这个版本还是旧的版本？
DAVID MALAN: This version or-- this version here or the old version?
观众：老版本
AUDIENCE: The old version.
大卫·马兰：好的 这很公平
DAVID MALAN: OK, that's fair.
事实上 我今天非常小心 尽我所能 不要搞砸了
And in fact, I'm being very careful today, as best I can, not to mess up.
到目前为止 我只输入整数 当我期待整数
I have thus far only inputted integers when I'm expecting integers.
拉乌尔实际上在指着什么东西
And Raoul's actually pointing to something
我们会在接下来的几周里继续讨论 我们实际上是如何处理错误的？
we'll come back to in the coming weeks, how do we actually handle errors?
如果用户没有输入数字1或数字2
What if the user doesn't type in the number 1 or the number 2, or a number
一点都不吗
at all?
如果他们输入一个词 如猫 C-A-T？
What if they type in a word like cat, C-A-T?
这不是一个数字 我打赌我不能把它转换成整数
That's not a number, and I bet I can't convert it to an integer.
但今天 我不会把重点放在这上面
But for today, I'm not going to focus on that.
我只希望用户能合作
I'm just going to hope that the user cooperates.
但事实并非如此
But that's not going to be the case.
所以也许有一种方法可以让我们取得更大的成功
And so perhaps one way would set us up for more success
当涉及到处理这些错误
when it comes to handling those errors.
就今天的目的而言 哪一个更好？
Now for today's purposes, which is better?
呃 我是说 我两个都喜欢
Eh, I mean, I like both.
我认为你们两个都提出了非常有效的论点
And I think both of you made very valid arguments in there too,
只要你有合理的理由
so long as you have a justification that feels pretty reasonable.
我是说 这才是最重要的
I mean, that's what ultimately matters.
但是 再次获得一种权衡的感觉
But acquiring, again, a sense of the trade-offs here.
这样好点吗
Well, is this way better?
如果是 原因是什么？
If so, why or why not?
只是了解这些权衡是什么
Just understanding what those trade-offs are.
但总的来说 优先考虑可读性是一件非常好的事情
But generally speaking, prioritizing readability is a very good thing.
让你的代码对其他人可读是一件非常好的事情
Making your code readable for someone else is a very good thing
对你也有好处 所以当你第二天早上醒来时
and very good for you too so that when you wake up the next morning,
或者下周或者明年再来
or you come back the next week, or the next year,
你也可以读你自己的代码 而不必浪费
you too can read your own code without having to waste
花时间回忆你做了什么
time trying to remember what you did.
而且简单往往也是一件好事--保持代码简单
And simplicity tends to be a good thing too-- keeping your code simple.
所以当你对编程越来越熟悉的时候
So as you get more comfortable with programming,
您可能会尝试将整个程序合并为一个长行
you might be tempted to try to combine an entire program into one long line.
例如 让我来做这个
For instance, let me do just that.
从技术上讲 我们并不需要变量中的x
Technically speaking, we don't really need x in a variable.
我们不需要变量中的y
We don't really need y in a variable.
我们也可以这样做
We could also do this--
我可以把x和y一起去掉
I could just get rid of x and y altogether.
然后 我现在可以去掉它 使其只有一行代码
I could then now eliminate that and make it just one line of code.
好的 所以在某种意义上 你可能会想 哇
OK, so on some sense, you might be inclined to think, wow,
真是太好了
that's really nice.
你让它变成了一行简单的代码
You made it one simple line of code.
我会争辩说 这实际上并没有那么简单
I would argue this actually isn't that simple.
现在我想我开始筑巢太多东西了
Now I think I'm starting to nest too many things.
我必须考虑打印、int和输入
I have to think about print and INT and input.
然后我必须注意到 好的 我打开了两个括号
I then have to notice that, OK, I've opened two parentheses,
我已经关闭了其中两家
I've closed two of them.
有一个+
There's a +.
你让我想得太多了 任何时候你让我想
You're making me think too much and any time you make me think,
你在浪费时间
you're wasting time.
任何时候 当你把代码的外观复杂化时
And any time you complicate the look of the code like this,
你只会增加犯错的可能性
you're just going to increase the probability of mistakes
以及代码中的战术错误或逻辑错误
and tactical mistakes or logical errors in your code.
因此 如果我们所做的所有事情 这是我唯一要争辩的
So if all the things we've done, this is the only one that I would argue,
是的 只有一条线路 又漂亮又紧凑
yes, it's one line and it's nice and compact.
它只是可读性不够
It's just not readable enough.
我会避免这样做 特别是因为其中两个函数
I would shy away from doing this, especially since two of those function
呼叫正在从用户处获得输入
calls are getting input from the user.
但在那里 理性的人可能不会同意
But there too, reasonable people might disagree,
但这是一种你有时应该有的本能反应
but that's the kind of visceral reaction you should have sometimes when
代码开始变得有点太复杂 有点太聪明
code starts getting a little too complicated, a little too clever,
也许 这是为了它的利益
perhaps, for its own good.
好吧 我们不只是能接触到整数
All right, well it's not just integers we have access to.
让我建议在这里将整数转换为另一种数据类型
Let me propose that we transition from integers to one more data type here,
也就是浮点
namely a float.
同样 字符串是一系列文本
So again, a string is a sequence of text.
整数是像负1、0和1一样的整数
An INT is an integer like negative 1, 0 and 1.
浮点数是一个带有小数点的数字 恰当地称为浮点数
A float is a number with a decimal point, properly called a floating point
价值
value.
你可以把浮点数想象成
And you can think of the floating point as being
可能在这里或这里的小数位数
the decimal that might be over here or over here with some number of digits
向左或向右
to the left or the right.
从数学上讲 它是一个实数 一个有小数点的数字
Mathematically, it's a real number, a number that has a decimal point in it.
这是第三种类型的数据 也就是Python支持的数据
So that's a third type of data that Python supports.
现在我们的计算器有点幼稚
Right now our calculator is somewhat naively
假设用户仅要键入整数
assuming that the user is only going to type in integers,
但如果我也想支持浮点值
but if I want to support floating point values too,
我想我可以做几个小调整
I think I can just make a couple of tweaks.
所以我要回到VS代码这一点
So I'm going to go back to VS Code here.
并且不是仅仅将用户的输入x和y转换为
And instead of just converting the user's input x and y to
第一行和第二行的整数 让我们做一个简单的更改
integers on line 1 and 2, let's just make a simple change.
让我们将其实际转换为第一行的浮点数
Let's actually convert it to a float on the first line
在这里的第二行有一个花车
and a float on the second line here.
现在我想 如果我下到我的终端窗口并运行Calculator.py的Python
Now I think, if I go down to my terminal window and run Python of Calculator.py,
让我们输入一个带小数点的数字 比如1.2
let's type in a number like 1.2 with a decimal point
加上一个小数点的3.4 我们就开始了
and 3.4 with a decimal point, and there we go.
我们的最终答案是4.6
We have 4.6 as the final answer.
因此 如果我只期待整数 这在以前是行不通的
So that wouldn't have worked before if I was only expecting integers
来自用户的值 但现在我需要浮点值
from the user, but now that I'm expecting floating point values
适应它 我现在实际上也可以做浮点算术了
and accommodating it, I can actually now do floating point arithmetic as well.
但假设我并不真正想要最终的答案
But suppose that I don't really want the final answer
设置为浮点值 如4.6
to be a floating point value like 4.6.
如果我们只舍入到最接近的整数 我会很高兴
I would be happy if we just round to the nearest integer.
所以我想支持用户在浮点打字
So I want to support the user typing in floating point
带有小数点的值 但在一天结束时
values with decimal points, but at the end of the day,
例如 我只想将结果四舍五入为最接近的整数
I just want to round the result to the nearest possible integer, for instance.
事实证明 在这里 也有一些内置的功能
Well it turns out that here too Python comes with some functionality built in.
事实上 如果我们返回到前面的URL
And in fact, if we return to this URL from earlier
其中列出了所有的Python内置函数
wherein all of the Python built-in functions are listed,
有一种叫“圆形”的词 它的意思是
there's one called "round" which does exactly
正如我们所期望的那样 它接受一个数字作为输入
as we would expect, it takes as input a number
然后为我们将其舍入为最接近的整数
and then rounds it for us, for instance, to the nearest integer.
但如果我们像这里一样更仔细地查看这些文档--
But if we look a little closer at that documentation as we can here--
我将提供一段摘录--
I'll provide an excerpt--
文档中的函数如下所示
this is what the function looks like in the documentation.
回想一下 前面我们查看了打印的文档
And recall that earlier we looked at the documentation for print
这在精神上是相似的 这向我们展示的不仅仅是
and this is similar in spirit that this shows us not just
函数的名称 但其可用参数 即
the name of the function but its available parameters, that is,
使用此函数时我们可以提供的输入
inputs that we can provide when using this function.
但这也有点神秘 就像印刷品一样
But this is a little cryptic too, just like Print was,
它还添加了一些语法
and it adds some syntax.
让我们来看看
So let's see.
这里这个函数的名称当然是RUND
The name of this function here is of course Round
它的第一个参数是一个数字
and its first argument is a number.
注意 这一次没有恒星 没有恒星物体
Notice this time there's no star, there's no star objects
就像印刷品一样
like there was for print.
ROUND函数只接受一个数字作为其第一个参数Period
The Round function takes just one number as its first argument, period.
这是它的位置参数
That's its positional parameter.
但请注意此语法
But notice this syntax.
这是编程或技术上的惯例
And this is a convention in programming or technology
更广泛地说 一般来说 当你看到方括号时
more generally, generally speaking, when you see square brackets
像这样的文件 这意味着你是
and documentation like this, this means that you're
即将看到一些可选的内容
about to see something optional.
这就意味着 如果你想
And so what this means is that if you want
为了更准确地指定希望ROUND函数的位数
to specify more precisely the number of digits that you want the round function
要四舍五入 您可以在此处指定 方法是添加逗号 然后添加该数字
to round to, you can specify it here by adding a comma and then that number.
因此 如果我们阅读文档 如果您不指定位数
So if we read the documentation, if you don't specify a number of digits,
您只需指定要舍入的数字 它就会舍入到最接近的整数
you just specify the number to round, it rounds to the nearest integer.
但是 假设您想要位于第10位或第100位
But suppose you want around to the tenths place, or the hundredths place
这是小数点后的一位或两位数
that is one or two digits after the decimal point,
更准确地说 您还可以传入逗号1或逗号2
you could additionally pass in comma 1 or comma 2 to be more precise.
这就是文件所说的
So that's what the documentation, there is saying.
让我们看看是否不能为我们将其转换为一些实际的代码
Let's see if we can't then translate this to some actual code for us.
所以如果我现在回到VS代码 我认为
So if I go back now to VS Code and I consider
我想要继续 对x和y进行循环 我可以用几种方法来做
that I want to go ahead and round x and y, I can do this in a couple of ways.
我可以做x+y轮 但你知道 我会
I could do round x + y, but you know, I'd
实际上 我更倾向于把这个问题分成两行
actually kind of prefer to break this now out into two lines.
我不需要 这里有理智的人可能不同意
I don't have to, and reasonable people here might disagree,
但我想回到打印z的场景中
but I'd like to revert to a scenario where I'm printing z,
这样我就能更清楚地了解自己 了解他人
so that I can just a little more clearly to myself, to others,
假设z=x+y的四舍五入结果
say z = the rounded result of x + y.
这并不一定是更好的方法
It's not necessarily the better way to do it,
但我更愿意一次说出我的一个想法
but I'm a little more comfortable with breaking out my thoughts one at a time,
尤其是如果我想要开始注释这些代码块中的每一个
especially if I want to start commenting each of these chunks of code.
好的 让我去我的终端窗口
All right, let me go down to my terminal window
现在运行Calculator.py的Python
now and run Python of Calculator.py.
X是什么？
What's x?
让我们再做一次1.2
Let's do 1.2 again.
那我们就做3.4吧
Then let's do 3.4.
现在之前是4.6 但现在是
And now it was previously 4.6, but now it's
向上舍入到最接近的整数 当然是5
been rounded up to the nearest integer, which of course is going to be 5.
好吧 如果我想进一步改变这一点呢？
All right, what if I wanted to change this a little further?
如果我想支持可能非常大的数字
What if I wanted to support maybe really big numbers,
大数字 不管四舍五入 让我们做这样的事情
big numbers, irrespective of rounding, let's just do something like this.
让我继续运行Calculator.py的Python
Let me go ahead and run Python of Calculator.py
让我再加一次999+1
again and let me just add 999 + 1.
注意 我不需要输入小数点
And notice, I don't have to type decimal points,
即使我要转换为浮点型 我的程序
even though I'm converting to float, my program
只允许我输入小数点 但我不需要这样做
will just allow me to type decimal points, but I don't need to oblige.
当然 这里的答案应该是 实际上也是1000
The answer of course here should be, and is in fact, 1,000,
不管我们是不是绕过去
whether or not we round.
所以这只是整数的算术
So that's just arithmetic with integers here.
但在美国 我们倾向于用逗号来格式化长数字
But in the US, we tend to format long numbers by putting commas
在每三位数之后或之前
after or before every triple of digits.
其他国家则改用句号和逗号
Other countries flip it and they use periods and commas instead.
这是一个系统设置
That's a system setting.
您可以在自己的Mac或PC上进行更改
You can change that on your own Mac or PC
或任何语言的设备 但对我来说 我是
or device for Python or any language, but for me, I'm
这里使用的是美国方法 即小数点的句号
using the US approach here, which is periods for decimal points
和逗号作为分隔符
and commas for separators.
如果我想将其输出为1,000 怎么办？
What if I wanted this to be outputted as 1,000?
只是想更清楚一点 它是1000 而不是100左右
Just to make it a little more clear that it's 1,000 and not something like 100.
当它达到100万的时候 这就更有用了--
That's even more useful when it's like one million--
一百万
1,000,000.
如果我们能自动地
Wouldn't it be nice if we could automatically
也输出这些数字吗？
output those numbers as well?
好吧 事实证明我们可以
Well, it turns out that we can.
有一种使用Python的方法可以实际指定我们
There is a way using Python to actually specify that we
我想包括这样的逗号
want to include commas like this.
现在我们有机会把我们的老朋友 F弦带回来
And here we have an opportunity to bring back our old friend, the F string.
首先 让我做一些不那么有成效的事情
First, let me do something that's not that productive.
首先 让我来做这个
First let me do this.
让我打印出z的值 但请稍等
Let me print out the value of z, but wait a minute.
我不能只说“z” 因为从字面上看 这会打印出z
I can't just say "z" because that's literally going to print z
在屏幕上
on the screen.
所以让我像以前一样用花括号把它包起来
So let me wrap it with those curly braces like I did before,
但这也是不够的
but that too was not enough.
我确实需要在字符串的开头添加一个F
I literally needed to add an F at the beginning of my string
来告诉Python这是一个F字符串 一种格式字符串
to tell Python that this is an F string, a format string.
现在将打印出来 不是很有趣 只是z的值
That now is going to print out, not very interestingly, just the value of z
它本身
itself.
所以我会不遗余力地打印z 而实际上我本可以
So I'm going to great lengths just to print z when really I could have just
把z作为唯一的论据
passed z as the sole argument.
但为了确保我没有弄坏它 让我们再来一次
But just to ensure that I haven't broken it, let's do this again.
999+1 回车
999 + 1, Enter.
好的 还是1000美元
OK, it's still 1,000.
所以我没有让事情变得更糟
So I didn't make anything worse.
但请注意--不幸的是 这个语法有点神秘--
But notice-- and this syntax is unfortunately a bit cryptic--
注意 我实际上可以做到这一点
notice that I can actually do this.
我可以在z后面加一个冒号 然后再加一个逗号
I can put a colon after the z and I can put a comma thereafter.
诚然 这看起来非常神秘 甚至我
This looks very cryptic, admittedly, and even I
我必须不断地在文档中查找类似的内容
have to constantly look things like this up in the documentation
记住语法
to remember the syntax.
但在这里 让我再运行一次
But here, let me run it again.
Python of Calculator.py 9991 现在请注意
Python of Calculator.py, 999 1 and now notice
号码是自动为我格式化的
that the number has been automatically formatted for me.
如果我在一个不同的国家或地区
If I were in a different country or locale,
我完全可以用句点来代替逗号或反之亦然
I could absolutely override this to use periods instead of commas or vise
反过来说
versa.
但在这种情况下 这对我来说是自动发生的
But in this case here, it's just happening for me automatically.
因此 我们在这里也看到了对真正格式化字符串意味着什么的暗示
So there too we see a hint of what it means to really format a string.
甚至还有更大的力量--
There's even more power--
其中内置了更强大的功能
more powerful capabilities built into that.
好的 让我在这里停一下 看看有没有
All right, let me pause here to see if there's
任何关于浮点数、四舍五入或F字符串用法的问题
any questions now on floats, on rounding, or on this use of F strings.
观众：是的 所以我有一个问题
AUDIENCE: Yes, so I have a question.
所以当使用花车时 有没有像帽子一样的东西
So when using floats, is there like a cap
到它可以有多少个小数点？
to how many decimal points it can have?
大卫·马兰：这是一个非常好的问题
DAVID MALAN: A really good question.
所以漂浮 是的 这是一个我们不久将重新讨论的问题
So floats, yes, and this is a problem we'll revisit before long.
浮点数不能无限精确地表示数字
Floats cannot represent numbers infinitely precisely.
一言以蔽之 因为计算机只有这么多的内存
In a nutshell, because computers only have so much memory.
它们只有有限的内存
They only have a finite amount of memory.
你和我在电脑里只有有限数量的硬件
You and I only have a finite amount of hardware inside of the computer,
因此 在某种程度上 他们将不得不绕过去
so at some point, they're going to have to round.
现在我正在自动取整
Right now I'm rounding automatically.
实际上 计算机最终将不得不为我们做到这一点
Effectively computers will eventually have to do that for us,
但不久之后 我们将把这视为一个根本问题
but we'll see that as a fundamental problem before long.
请允许我回到关于Float的最后几个例子
Allow me to turn back just for a few final examples on float
在我们介绍最后几个例子之前 这些例子不仅允许我们
before we introduce a few final examples that allow us not just
使用函数 但创建我们自己的函数
to use functions, but to make our own.
让我建议我们在这里也尝试一下点名表决
Let me propose that we also try our hands at a bit of division here.
让我提议我们现在修改这个计算器
Let me propose that we modify this calculator now
仍然带着几个花车 但现在让我们做
to still take a couple of floats, but let's now just do
比这更简单的东西--
something a little simpler than--
和这个略有不同 就是x除以y
a little different from this, just doing x divided by y.
让我继续 去掉我的格式字符串
And let me go ahead and get rid of my format string
现在只需保持简单 打印出z即可
and just keep it simple for now, printing out z instead.
我们在这里会看到什么呢？
And what are we going to see here?
嗯 只是一些简单的除法
Well just some simple division.
因此 在Calculator.py中 让我们做一些类似于2除以3的操作
So Python of Calculator.py, let's do something like 2 divided by 3,
当然 我能拿到0.66666
and of course I get 0.66666.
对于伊森刚才的问题 它似乎确实是有限的
And to Ethan's question a moment ago, it does seem to be finite.
它在这里不是以一种奇怪的方式舍入 但我似乎只看到这么多数字
It's not rounding in a weird way here, but I only seem to see so many digits.
这是以这种方式使用浮点的必然性
That's an inevitability of using a float in this way.
相比之下 正如您所知道的 现在在Python语言中使用整数
By contrast, just so you know, integers nowadays in Python
可以有多大就有多大
can be as big as you want them to be.
与其他语言不同 它没有上限
Unlike other languages, there is no upper bound
关于整数现在在Python语言中可以有多大 但有
on how big an INT can be now in Python, but there
是浮点值的精确度的界限
is a bound on just how precise a floating point value can be.
好的 现在我有了一个简单的部门
All right, now that I've got some simple division working here,
让我们继续下去 把这个绕过去
let's go ahead and round this.
对这个很长的数字0.6666666进行舍入会很好 依此类推
It would be nice to round this really long number 0.6666666 and so forth
可能只有两位小数点后
to maybe just two decimal places.
不过 我们已经看到了如何使用ROUND做到这一点 至少在它的文档中是这样的
We've seen how to do this with round, though, at least in its documentation.
让我们把它舍入到最接近的整数
Let's just round this not to the nearest INT,
通过只传递x除以y 这是一个参数 一旦数学是
by passing in just x divided by y, which is one argument, once the math is
在括号内完成 我不想只传递一个参数
done inside of the parentheses, I don't want to pass in just one argument.
我想传入两个数字 这样我就可以指定n位数字
I want to pass in two so that I can specify n digits,
位数 您还记得它是舍入的第二个参数
number of digits, which you'll recall was the second parameter for round.
让我继续运行Calculator.py的Python
Let me go ahead and run Python of Calculator.py.
我会做同样的事情--
I'll do the same thing--
2 然后是3 0.67
2 and then 3, 0.67.
所以我们现在也看到了一种取整的方法 不仅仅是舍入到最接近的整数
So here too we see a way of rounding now, not just to a nearest integer,
而是最接近的数字
but to a nearest number of digits.
但在这里 还有另一种方法可以做到这一点
But there's another way to do this here.
事实上 这再次唤起了我们的F字符串的例子
And in fact, this evokes our F string example again.
让我继续更改这一点
Let me go ahead and change this.
假设您不记得ROUND函数 或者 出于某种原因
Suppose that you didn't remember the round function or, for some reason,
你不想用它
you didn't want to use it.
相反 您只想使用格式字符串
You instead want to just use a format string.
好吧 我们去那里吧
Well, let's go there.
让我做“z” 但让我用花括号把它括起来
Let me do "z" but let me surround it with those curly braces.
让我在开头加上F 再一次 这还不是很有趣
Let me add the F at the beginning, and again, this is not interesting yet.
这只会打印出z 但我会增加更多的复杂性
This is just going to print out z, but I'm adding a lot more complexity
把它变成F弦
to turn it into an F string.
但请注意 我可以在变量名之后、冒号之后执行其他操作
But notice I can do something else after my variable name, after the colon.
如果这将是一个大整数 我
If this were going to be a big integer, I
可能需要像以前一样使用逗号来分隔每三个数字
might want to use a comma like before to separate each triple of numbers
用逗号
with commas.
但我不知道
But I don't.
我将使用不同的字符序列
I'm going to use a different sequence of characters.
我要说的是0.2F 这也是我有一个非常神秘的东西
I'm going to say 0.2F and this too is one of these very cryptic things I have
经常抬头 因为如果我不经常使用它 我会忘记
to constantly look up because I forget if I don't use it that often.
所以 如果这看起来特别奇怪 不要害怕 但这是
So don't be intimidated if this looks especially weird, but this is,
根据文件 你的方式
according to the documentation, the way you
使用F字符串指定要打印的位数
specify using an F string how many digits you want to print.
所以让我运行这个版本的计算器
So let me run this version of the calculator.
输入2 然后输入3 我们得到完全相同的结果
Type in 2 and then 3, we get the exact same thing.
但同样 这与我的主张是一致的
But again, this is just consistent with my claim
在编程中 我们经常可以解决相同的问题
that in programming we can so very often solve the same problem
以多种方式
in multiple ways.
这就是现在解决同样问题的F弦方法
This is just now the F string approach to that very same problem.
好的 哪一个更好？
All right, which one is better?
那得看情况
It depends.
在这种情况下 它们几乎是等价的
In this case, they're pretty equivalent.
不过 您可以想象 有时使用函数是很有用的
You can imagine, though, it being useful to use a function sometimes
这样您就可以将n位之类参数作为第二个参数进行传递
so that you can pass in an argument like n digits as that second argument,
或者您可以想象一下 您只需提前决定您想要0.2
or you can imagine just deciding in advance that you want 0.2
然后写成这样
and then writing it like this.
现在让我们从关注字符串和整数过渡到
Let's transition now from focusing on strings and on integers and on
现在重点放在函数本身上
floats to focusing now on functions themselves.
我们今天一开始就关注您如何
We began today by focusing on how you can
使用随Python提供的函数
use functions that come with Python.
但如果你能发明你自己的功能不是很好吗
But wouldn't it be nice if you could invent your own functions,
特别是如果 正如我们前面所说的 你会发现
especially if, to our point earlier, you find
你自己一次又一次地解决同样的问题？
yourself solving the same kind of problem again and again?
很好 Python附带了打印功能
It's nice that Python comes with the print function
因为能够在屏幕上打印东西真的很有用
because it's really useful to be able to print things on the screen,
但如果你可以在屏幕上打印特定的东西 那不是很好吗
but wouldn't it be nice if you could print specific things on the screen
只需调用您自己的函数？
by just calling your own function?
好吧 让我提议我们这样做
Well let me propose that we do this.
让我回到这里的VS代码 让我建议我们回到Hello.py
Let me go back to VS Code here and let me propose that we go back to Hello.py.
我要在之前离开的地方重新打开Hello.py
I'm going to reopen Hello.py where we left it before
现在我要开始向大家提出
and I'm going to go ahead now and propose
我们考虑如何才能开始进一步改善这一点
that we consider how we can start improving this further by making
我们自己的功能
our own function.
我今天写了很多程序 只是打个招呼
I have written so many programs today that just say Hello
每次我使用印刷品的时候
and each time I'm using print.
但如果从今天开始
But wouldn't it have been nice if, from the beginning of today,
我们可以只调用一个名为Hello的函数 该函数只为我们说Hello？
we could just call a function called Hello that just says Hello for us?
现在 多年前的Python的作者们并没有
Now the authors of Python years ago didn't
我想我们需要一个特殊的功能来打招呼
think that we need a special function just to say Hello,
但我希望这种情况能够存在
but I would like that to exist.
我打了很多次招呼 我只是想
I'm saying Hello so many times, I just want
为了能够调用函数Hello
to be able to call a function Hello.
因此 我将在这里从头开始
So I'm going to start from scratch here.
我将删除前面的所有代码
I'm going to delete all of my code from earlier
我暂时假设存在一个名为Hello的函数
and I'm going to pretend for the moment that a function called Hello exists.
我要做的就是像以前一样
And I'm going to do just as I did before.
我将使用输入函数获取用户名
I'm going to get the user's name with the input function,
问你叫什么名字 问号
asking what's your name, question mark.
现在我将调用函数Hello
And now I'm going to call a function Hello
然后我将打印出用户名
and then I'm going to print out the user's name.
现在我要承认 Hello并不存在 所以坏事就要发生了
Now I will admit, Hello doesn't exist, so bad things are about to happen,
但让我们来看看会发生什么
but let's see what.
让我下到我的终端窗口
Let me go down to my terminal window.
让我运行Hello.py的Python
Let me run Python of Hello.py.
我认为第一行会很好 因为这以前很管用
I think the first line is going to be OK because that worked before.
事实上 这促使我选择了我的名字
And indeed, it's prompting me for my name.
那么 让我输入David
So let me type in David.
第二行代码显然是在调用
The second line of code is apparently calling
一个看起来像是Hello的函数 因为它为什么是一个函数？
a function that looks like it's called Hello, because why is it a function?
它后面紧跟着一个括号和一个右括号
It has a parenthesis and a closed parenthesis immediately after it.
这就是我们用过的每个函数的样子
And that's what every function we've used has looked like.
但是 Python不会识别这一点
But Python is not going to recognize this one.
现在 当我按Enter键时 我得到一个名称错误
When I hit Enter now, I get a name error.
未定义名称“Hello” 您的意思是帮助吗？
Name "Hello" is not defined, did you mean Help?
我没有 虽然这是个好时机我现在需要的是帮助
I didn't, although it's opportune that's what I need at this point is some help,
但我遇到这个错误是因为什么呢？
but I am encountering this error because why?
这个功能根本不存在
The function just doesn't exist.
那么 我如何让这个函数存在呢？
So how do I make this function exist?
嗯 我需要自己创建它 使用这个关键字 DEF 定义的DEF
Well I need to create it myself using this key word, DEF, DEF for define.
所以这里也是一样 就像STR是字符串的缩写 int是整数的缩写
So here too, just as STR is short for string and INT is short for integer,
Def是定义的缩写
DEF is short for define.
如果您想要定义、创建、发明您自己的函数
If and when you want to define, create, invent your own functions,
现在 您可以在Python中使用此关键字来完成此操作
you can do so using now this keyword in Python.
让我回到我这里的代码 让我建议我们定义这个
So let me go back to my code here and let me propose that we define this
也许是以这种方式
perhaps in this way.
在我文件的最顶端 我将首先
At the very top of my file, I'm going to first take
片刻定义一个名为Hello的函数
a moment to define a function called Hello
使用DEF Hello 左括号 右括号 冒号
using DEF Hello, open parenthesis, close parenthesis, colon.
现在的意思是 Python将处理每一行代码
What this means now is that Python is going to treat every line of code
我在这个下面缩进 作为这个新函数的含义 Hello
that I indent underneath this one as the meaning of this new function, Hello.
所以DEF很重要 空间也很重要
So DEF is important as is the space.
我可以选择函数的名称 我选择将其命名为Hello
I get to choose the name of the function and I'm choosing to call it Hello.
括号内没有任何内容 表示此函数此时
The parentheses with nothing inside means that this function at the moment
不会接受任何输入 也不会有任何论点
is not going to take any inputs, no arguments there too.
冒号的意思是 请继续关注一些缩进
The colon means, stay tuned for some indentation.
这行代码下面缩进的所有内容
Everything that's indented beneath this line of code
将成为这一功能的一部分
is going to be part of this function.
这将是一个超短的函数--一行代码--
It's going to be a super short function-- one line of code--
它只会打印出“你好 ”
it's just going to print out "Hello."
但现在在第1行和第2行 我发明了我自己的函数Hello
But now on lines 1 and 2, I have invented my own function Hello.
注意这些现在神奇地出现在这里的圆点
Notice these dots that have now magically appeared here.
这只是我的文本编辑器的一个设置
This is just a setting of my text editor,
VS代码在这种情况下 这对我来说是非常明确的 我已经
VS Code in this case, that's just making super explicit to me that I've
按空格键四次 或相当于按Tab键一次
hit the space bar four times, or equivalently the Tab key once,
它被自动转换为四个空格
which is converted automatically to four spaces.
一般来说 我需要确保我所有的缩进代码
Generally speaking, I'm going to need to make sure that all of my indented code
现在排好队 这样Python就知道它们都是同一件事的一部分
lines up now so that Python knows that it's all part of the same thing.
但在本例中很容易 因为它只有一行
But it's easy in this case because it's just a single line.
但是现在 由于有了第1行和第2行 函数Hello
But now, thanks to lines 1 and 2, the function Hello
当我准备好在第6行使用它时 它将绝对存在
will absolutely exist when I'm ready to use it on line 6.
因此 让我转到我的终端窗口并运行Hello.py的Python 回车
So let me go down to my terminal window and run Python of Hello.py, Enter.
我的名字又来了
Here comes my name again.
现在 当我按回车键时 我现在看到的是Hello David
And now when I hit Enter, I now see Hello, David.
好吧 我们有点退步了 对吧？
All right, we've kind of regressed though, right?
这远不像以前那么漂亮了
This is not nearly as pretty as it once was.
我认为 通过进一步改进 我们可能会做得更好
I think we can probably do better than this by improving things further.
然而 我们为什么不考虑一下 我们可以如何
Why don't we consider, though, how we might
比如说 将这个相同的函数参数化？
say parameterize this same function?
也就是说 我们是否可以将Hello定制为可能将用户名作为输入
That is to say, can we customize Hello to maybe take the user's name as input
这样我们就可以说 不仅是你好 而且这个人的名字都在一行上 所有的
so that we can say, not only Hello, but the person's name all on one line, all
一口气？
in one breath?
我想我们可以做到的
Well I think we can do this.
让我提议我们这样做
Let me propose that we do this as follows.
让我在我的代码中继续前进 让我进入这些括号
Let me go ahead and up in my code, let me inside of these parentheses,
让我想出我自己的参数名称
let me come up with my own parameter name.
我在这里有完全的选择 我要去
I have complete choice here and I'm going
要说我的参数的名称将是单词
to say that the name of my parameter will be the word To.
为什么？
Why?
因为我希望我的函数听起来像它所代表的动词--
Because I want my function to sound like the verb it represents--
你好
Hello.
但是你想跟谁打个招呼呢？
But who do you want to say Hello to?
我将调用此函数的参数
Well I'm going to call my parameter for this function
To 就因为在英语里 它对我来说听起来很好听
To, just because in English, it kind of sounds nice to me.
你好 你想跟谁打个招呼？
Hello To, who do you want to say Hello to?
这就是为什么我调用这个参数而不是某个
That's why I'm calling this parameter To instead of something
更简单 如x、y或z
simpler like x or y or z.
好吧 那么我想用to这个词做什么呢？
All right, well what do I want to do with the word To?
嗯 我可以做几件不同的事情
Well I can do a couple of different things.
我们已经看到了很多不同的实现Hello的方法
We've seen like so many different ways to implement Hello.
为了语法起见 让我在那里加一个逗号
Let me just add a comma there for grammar's sake.
然后让我把后面的词作为第二个论点
And then let me put the word To after that as the second argument
转到函数Hello
to the function Hello.
我们还有其他方法可以做到这一点 我们已经看到了很多种方法
There's other ways we can do this and we've seen so many,
但我会说 这件事在我看来有点清楚
but this one looks a little clear to me, I'll say.
接下来会发生什么？
What's going to happen next?
我想我这里不需要这条额外的打印线
Well I don't think I need this extra print line here.
我想我要做的是 我要在这里继续
I think what I'm going to do is this, I'm going to go ahead here
而不是手动打印出这个人的名字 我会说
and print out not the person's name manually, I'm going to instead say,
你好 圆括号的名字
Hello parentheses name.
那么我现在在做什么呢？
So what am I now doing?
在第1行和第2行 我定义了我自己的函数 名为Hello
On lines 1 and 2 I'm defining my very own function called Hello,
但这一次 这个函数已经设计好了
but this time that function has been designed
接受一个参数 单个参数 作为输入
to take a parameter, a single parameter, as input.
我使用的是该参数的值
And I'm using the value of that parameter which
我打电话去印刷 这样我不仅能看到
I called To to plug into print so that I see not only
你好 还有那个人的名字
Hello but also that person's name.
我在5号线上做什么？
What am I doing on line 5?
和往常一样 我只是得到了用户名
Same as always, I'm just getting the user's name.
6号线 我不仅要打给你 我要路过
Line 6, I'm not only calling Hello, I'm passing
作为作为参数的名称变量的输入
as input the name variable as an argument
所以这就是传递给Hello的内容
so that that's what gets passed into Hello.
这里发生的事情本质上是这样的--
And what's happening here is essentially this--
即使变量在这里称为NAME 当函数
even though the variable is called Name here, when the function
自身被调用时 计算机假定现在调用了相同的值
itself is called, the computer assumes that same value is now called To.
因此 名称实际上被复制到另一个名为
So Name is essentially copied to another variable called
这样 在Hello的上下文中 我可以对该变量说Hello
To so that in the context of Hello, I can say Hello to that variable instead.
我们很快就会看到 如果我们不把这些放在一起会发生什么
And we'll see in a moment what happens if we don't keep those straight.
让我继续运行Hello.py的Python 回车
Let me go ahead and run Python of Hello.py, Enter.
你叫什么名字？
What's your name?
现在我要祈祷了
And now I'm crossing my fingers.
进来吧
Enter.
我们走吧
There we go.
我们恢复了业务 但现在我有了自己的定制函数 名为Hello
We're back in business, but now I have my own custom function called Hello
这让我可以向特定的人打招呼
that's allowing me to say Hello to a specific person.
这就是现在事情可以变得非常奇特的地方
And here's where now things can get really fancy.
如果你想让你的Hello函数向某个特定的人问好
What if you wanted your Hello function to say Hello to someone specific,
但是 你知道吗 如果你不知道你想跟谁打招呼
but, you know what, if you don't know who you want to say Hello to,
你想向全世界问好
you want to say Hello to the whole world,
您可以为参数指定缺省值
you can give parameters default values.
我们已经看到了这一点
We've seen that.
回想一下 对于Print SEP有一个缺省值
Recall that with print there was a default value for SEP,
作为分隔器
for the separator.
End有一个缺省值 即行结束
There was a default value for END, the line ending.
我们也可以这样做 下面是语法
We can do that too, and here's the syntax.
如果您想要此参数的默认值
If you want the value of this parameter by default,
如果不是由程序员提供的 则等于“world”
if not provided by the programmer, to be equal to "world,"
你可以在定义函数的同一行中做到这一点
you literally do that in the same line you're defining the function.
我承认 它开始看起来更神秘了
And I'll admit, it's starting to look more cryptic,
但我仍在定义一个名为Hello的函数 它
but I'm still just defining a function called Hello, it
接受一个名为的参数 但我将其赋值
takes a parameter called To, but I'm assigning it
用等号表示缺省值“world” 以防程序员
with the equal sign a default value of "world," just in case the programmer
不使用参数调用Hello
doesn't call Hello with an argument.
我们可以在这里看到这个
And we can see this here.
让我更改代码 以两种方式使用Hello
Let me change my code to use Hello in two ways.
在第5行 我将非常简单地调用Hello no arguments
On line 5, I'm going to very simply call Hello, no arguments.
然后在第6行 我将得到名字
Then on line 6, I'm going to get the name.
第7行 我将用一个参数调用Hello
Line 7, I'm going to call Hello with an argument.
因此 您将看到Hello现在被以两种方式使用
So you'll see Hello now being used in two ways.
让我继续运行Hello.py的Python
Let me go ahead and run Python of Hello.py.
我要把我的名字打进去
I'll type in my name.
哦 有意思
Oh, interesting.
请注意 我已经看到了Hello World 但这是
Notice I already see Hello, world, but that's
因为第5行在第6行之前 所以是预期的 但是一旦我输入我的名字
expected because line 5 happens before line 6, but once I type my name,
现在节目将会更有礼貌地跟我打招呼
now the program is going to be a little more polite and say hello to me
就个人而言
personally.
在那里 我们也可以看到相对简单但新的语法
So there too, we see with relatively simple but new syntax
如何实现与印刷品在本质上非常相似的功能
how you can implement functionality very similar in spirit to what the print
功能自动给了我们
function gave us automatically.
现在你可以控制自己做这件事了
Now you have control over doing that yourself.
但现在让我也说明这一点
But let me now make this point too.
定义您自己的函数的全部要点之一
One of the whole points of defining your own functions
是一种 只是为了避免一次又一次地重复自己
is one, just to avoid having to repeat yourself again and again.
你不需要一直重新发明轮子
You don't have to actually keep reinventing the wheel
并继续使用打印功能 一次又一次
and keep using the print function again, and again, and again,
如果你只是想跟我打个招呼
if you just want to say Hello.
如果我现在可以移动这个代码不是很好吗
Wouldn't it be nice now if I could move this code
这是我为定义Hello函数而编写的 只是为了戏剧性地说
that I wrote for defining the Hello function, and just to be dramatic,
我要多次按回车键 50行以下
I'm going to hit Enter a whole lot of times, 50 lines down,
并将我对Hello way的定义进一步放在这个文件中
and put my definition of Hello way further down in this file.
为什么？
Why?
好吧 只是为了本着眼不见心不烦的精神
Well, just for in the spirit of out of sight, out of mind,
因为如果我现在回放到我的节目的开头 现在
because if I now rewind to the start of my program, now
你可以想当然地认为 哦 Hello是一个函数
you can take for granted that, oh, Hello is a function.
为什么？
Why?
因为它在第一行 它有一个左括号和一个闭合括号
Because it's there on line 1 and it has an open parenthesis and a closed
括号 到目前为止 它的意思是调用这个函数
parenthesis, which, up until now has meant, call this function.
然后在第2行 我们从用户那里获得一个变量
And then on line 2 we're getting a variable from the user
然后我们调用Hello 传入这个值
by typing in their name and then we're calling Hello, passing in that value.
在这一点上 我可以理所当然地认为Hello存在
Well at this point, I can just take for granted that Hello exists,
即使它在文件中的位置更低 或者正如我们在未来几周看到的那样
even if it's way down further in the file or, as we'll see in future weeks,
即使是在另一个文件里
even if it's in a different file altogether.
但这里有个问题
But there's a problem here.
让我继续运行这个版本的Hello.py
And let me go ahead and run this version of Hello.py.
请注意 只要我运行解释器 Hello.py的Python
Notice that as soon as I run the interpreter, Python of Hello.py,
我看到一个名称错误 名称Hello未定义
I see a name error, name Hello is not defined.
再说一遍 你是说帮助吗？
Again, did you mean Help?
好吧 再一次 合适
Well, again, fitting.
我确实需要一些帮助 但我并不想调用Help函数
I do need some help here, but I didn't mean to call the function Help.
然而 这里的问题是 Python只是从字面上理解我
The problem here, though, is that Python is just taking me literally.
我已经定义了函数Hello一直到这里
I have defined my function Hello all the way down here,
但我想把它用在这里
but I'm trying to use it way up here.
这是不允许的
And that's not allowed.
Python的解释器将从字面上理解
Python's interpreter is going to take you literally
如果你使用一个函数 它必须已经
and if you use a function, it must already
在你打电话的时候就存在了
exist by the time you are calling it.
我该怎么解决这个问题？
So how do I fix this?
显然我不能这么做
Well, apparently I can't do that.
我必须在文件的最顶端定义任何函数
I have to define any functions I want at the very top of my file,
但这也会给我带来麻烦
but that too could get me into a bit of trouble
因为如果我总是要定义一个函数
eventually because if I constantly have to define a function above where I want
要使用它 你需要反向编写代码
to use it, you're kind of writing code in reverse,
你不断地在这里写函数 在这里
you're constantly writing functions up here, up here,
在这里 相对于逻辑地写代码 从上到下
up here, as opposed to writing your code logically, top to bottom.
让我用一种更标准的方法来解决这个问题 就是这样做
So let me fix this in a more standard way, which is to do this.
一般来说 您确实希望将代码的主要部分
Generally speaking, you do want to put the main part of your code
在你档案的顶部
at the top of your file.
实际上 我将定义一个函数 叫做Main
And in fact, I'm going to go so far as to define my function, called Main.
这不是一个要求 但它是在数据公约
It's not a requirement, but it's in data convention,
这就向读者暗示了
and this just connotes to the reader that this
是我的计划的主要部分
is the main part of my program.
我现在要去掉空的Hello调用 只传入一个版本
I'm going to get rid of my empty Hello call now and only pass in one version
你好 名字
with Hello, name.
再往下 再往下几行
And then down here, a couple of lines further down,
实际上 我将定义我的Hello函数
I'll actually define my Hello function.
不幸的是 现在我已经以这种方式重新排序了函数
Unfortunately, now that I've reordered the functions in this way,
我把代码的主要部分放在顶部 Hello放在底部
by putting the main part of my code at the top and Hello at the bottom
这样我的逻辑就可以从上到下
so that my logic kind of flows top to bottom, if I go ahead and run
Hello.py的Python 输入
Python of Hello.py, Enter.
什么都没发生
Nothing whatsoever happens.
如果我再做一次 什么都不会发生
If I do it again, nothing whatsoever happens.
这到底是为什么
Well, why in the world is this?
我定义了一个函数
Well, just because I've defined a function called
Main和我定义了一个叫Hello的函数
Main and I've defined a function called Hello,
并不意味着我真的打过电话
doesn't mean that I've actually called--
这两种都是
that is used-- either of them.
是的 我在Main内部使用Hello 但没有人
Yes, I'm using Hello inside of Main, but no one
告诉Python实际使用或调用Main
is telling Python to actually use or call Main.
为了整理好这个文件 我最后要做的就是
So in order to tidy this up, the last thing I need to do in this file,
实际上是调用我的main函数
it seems, is actually call my main function.
实际上 通过这样调用我的main函数
And, in fact, by calling my main function in this way,
它让我摆脱了麻烦 因为现在我先定义Main
it gets me out of trouble because now I'm defining Main first
但我还没打给你
but I'm not calling Hello yet.
我将定义Hello next 但我不会调用Hello next
I'm defining Hello next, but I'm not calling Hello next.
我只在这个文件的最后调用Main
I only at the very end of this file call Main
它的作用是在这里运行这段代码
which has the effect of running this code up here,
which has the effect of running this code down here,
因此我可以整理我的档案
and it allows me therefore to organize my file
并以任何我想要的方式排列我的函数 包括顶部的Main
and order my functions in any way I want, including Main at the very top,
并最终解决Python不知道发生了什么的问题
and solving ultimately that problem of Python not knowing what's going on.
需要注意的是 我定义了函数
Now it's important to note that I defined my function
你好 作为一个论点 然后我
Hello as taking an argument To and then I
将变量的值传入该函数
passed into that function the value of the variable
我想跟它打个招呼 它就是名为Name的变量
that I wanted to say Hello to, that is the variable called Name.
因为假设我做了一些不同的事情
Because suppose I had done something a little bit differently.
假设我没有定义Hello是接受一个参数
Suppose that I hadn't defined Hello is taking an argument,
所以我只删除了对To及其默认值“world”提及 “
so I just remove mention of To and its default value "world."
我回到我的主函数
And I go back up to my main function and I just
调用Hello本身而不传入任何参数
call Hello itself without passing in any arguments.
现在让我继续做我的最后一件改变
And now let me go ahead and make my one more change,
技术上还有一个错误 让我继续
one more mistake technically, let me go ahead
并尝试简单地打印出Hello函数中的名称的值
and just try to naively print out the value of Name in the Hello function.
现在需要说明的是 在我第2行的主函数中
So now to be clear, in my main function on line 2,
我定义了名为name的变量 并将返回值赋给它
I'm defining my variable called Name and assigning it the return value
来自用户的输入功能
of the input function from the user.
然后我就给你打个电话
I'm then just calling Hello.
在我的Hello函数中 它现在不再接受任何参数
In my Hello function, which now no longer takes any arguments,
我正在调用Print 传入Hello逗号
I am calling print, passing in Hello comma,
然后立即传入名称、变量
and then immediately passing in Name, the variable
我得到了用户的输入
into which I got the user's input.
但问题是 这个名字现在只存在于Main中
But the catch is that name exists now only in Main.
所以 当我尝试运行这个版本的程序时 请注意会发生什么
And so watch what happens when I try to run this version of the program
使用Python Hello.py
with Python Hello.py.
我按了Enter键
I hit Enter.
我被提示输入我的名字 D-A-V-I-D 回车
I'm prompted for my name, D-A-V-I-D, Enter.
还有 啊！
And, argh!
名称错误
A name error.
未定义名称“name”
Name "Name" is not defined.
因此 这实际上是一个所谓范围的问题
So it turns out that this is actually an issue of what's called scope.
作用域是指仅存在于定义该变量的上下文中的变量
Scope refers to a variable only existing in the context in which you defined it.
因此 只要我定义了这个变量 在我的Main函数中命名
So insofar as I define this variable, Name in my main function,
我只能在我的名字函数中使用该变量
I can only use that variable in my name function.
我不能像我在Hello函数中尝试的那样使用它
I can't use it as I've tried to here in my Hello function.
它不存在于那个所谓的范围内
It doesn't exist in that so-called scope.
这就是为什么现在 如果我倒回并撤销所有这些更改
And so this is why now, if I rewind and undo all of those changes,
您将看到我故意从Main函数中传递Main
you'll see that I'm deliberately passing Main from my main function
进入我的Hello函数
into my Hello function.
现在在Hello函数中 从技术上讲 它有一个不同的名称
And now in the Hello function, it technically has a different name.
在这种情况下 它被要求这样做 但这很好
It's called To in that context, but that's fine.
命名自己的变量完全由每个单独的函数决定
It's completely up to each individual function to name its own variables
或者命名自己的论点 但这是现在的一种方式
or name its own arguments, but this is a way now
我将该变量的值传递给Hello函数
that I'm handing to the Hello function the value of that variable
所以它也可以由Hello打印
so it can be printed by Hello as well.
我们还可以在这里添加最后一个华丽的元素
And there's one final flourish we can add here.
现在我们已经实现了Hello 您会注意到Hello Only
Now that we've implemented Hello, you'll notice that Hello only
有所谓的副作用
has a so-called side effect.
它只将某些内容打印到屏幕上
It only prints out something to the screen.
好吧 如果我也希望我的功能本身不会有副作用
Well, what if I also want my function to not have a side effect, per se,
但真的给了我一个价值吗？
but actually hand me back a value?
回想一下 输入函数返回一个值
Recall that the input function returns a value,
用户键入的字符串
the string that the user typed in.
回想一下 int函数返回值
Recall that the INT function returns a value.
FLOAT函数返回传递给它的值
The float function returns a value that was passed into it.
你可以在这里使用最后一个关键词 字面意思
Well you can use one final keyword here, literally
返回可自己显式返回值
Return to return a value explicitly yourself.
事实上 让我回到这里的VS代码 我
In fact, let me go back to VS Code here, and I
我想我们会把注意力放在Calculator.py上
think we'll return our attention to Calculator.py
看看我们是否不能实现另一个版本的Calculator.py
and see if we can't implement one other version of Calculator.py that actually
有我们自己的函数 甚至返回值
has our own function that even returns a value.
所以我将继续打开Calculator/Py
So I'm going to go ahead and open up calculator/py
我想这一次我会像以前一样把一切都扔掉
and I think this time I'm going to throw everything away as before,
我要开始练习我们在这里所宣扬的东西
and I'm just going to start practicing what we're preaching here.
定义一个名为Main的函数 该函数现在
Define a function called Main which is now going
成为我职能的主要部分
to be the main part of my function.
我们继续 现在声明一个名为x的变量
Let's go ahead and now declare a variable called x,
并在询问他们之后将其分配给用户输入的转换版本
and assign it to the converted version of the user's input after asking them,
X是什么？
what's x?
再说一遍 这一行代码和我们以前做过的一样
So again, a line of code quite like we've done before.
现在假设我想要做的是对这个值进行平方
And suppose now that what I want to do is square this value.
我想取用户输入的号码
I want to take the number that the user has typed in
并将其乘以2的幂
and raise it to the power of 2.
所以2的平方等于4
So 2 squared would be 4.
3的平方等于9
3 squared would be 9.
4的平方等于16 以此类推
4 squared would be 16, and so forth.
那么我该如何逐字实现一个函数呢
Well how do I go about implementing a function literally
名为Square的应用程序实际上并没有内置Python？
called Square which actually doesn't come with Python built-in?
好吧 让我暂时假设它确实存在 并让
Well, let me assume for the moment that it does exist, and let
我这样说--
me say something like this--
让我继续说 印刷 如何
let me go ahead and say that printing, how
大约x的平方是x的逗号平方
about x squared is comma square of x.
那么我做了什么呢？
So what have I done?
我定义了一个名为main的函数 并实现了两行
I've defined a function called Main and I've implemented two lines.
这些行中的第一行提示用户输入值
The first of these lines prompts the user for a value
X并将其转换为int 并将其存储在一个名为x的变量中
x and converts it to an INT and stores it in a variable called x.
在第三行 我说x的平方是 然后
On line 3, I then say x squared is and then
我将第二个参数传递给print函数 无论返回什么
I pass a second argument to the print function, whatever the return
Value是一个平方函数
value is of a square function.
但是平方是不存在的 我会在这里展示给你们看
But squared doesn't exist and I'll show you this here,
如果我现在调用底部的Main 并运行Calculator.py的Python
if I now call Main at the bottom and I run Python of Calculator.py,
我会看到x是2 然后我会看到一大堆错误 一个名字错误
I'll see that x is 2 and then I see a whole bunch of errors, a name error,
未定义名称Square
name Square is not defined.
所以这不是一个打字错误 只是这个函数不存在
So this isn't a typo here, it's just the function doesn't exist.
但我想我可以让它在这里存在
But I think I can make it exist here.
让我们继续定义另一个名为Square的函数
Let me go ahead and define another function called Square.
这一张将会有一个数字 我是
This one's going to take in a number and I'm
就像许多程序员所说的那样 将其泛称为n
going to call it generically n, as many a programmer would,
只是为了代表任何旧数字
just to represent any old number.
然后我要怎么做才能求n的平方呢？
And then what do I want to do in order to square n?
嗯 一个数字的平方实际上就是它自己的乘积
Well a number squared is really just itself times itself,
所以我要这么做--
so I'm going to do this--
N乘以n
n times n.
但光靠自己算算是不够的 n乘以n
But it's not enough just to do the math yourself, n times n.
您将必须返回实际值n乘以n
You're going to have to return the actual value n times n
这就是我们的新关键词
and that's our new keyword here.
当我现在这样做的时候 看看会发生什么
When I now do this, watch what happens.
在Calculator.py的Python中 输入
Python of Calculator.py, Enter.
X说应该是2 x的平方是4
X say shall be 2, x squared is 4.
现在让我继续 假设x现在是3
Let me go ahead now and say x is now 3.
X的平方现在是9
X squared is now 9.
所以我实现了我自己的函数 它返回值的平方
So I've implemented my very own function that returns the square of a value
因为我使用的是返回关键字 所以
and because I'm using the return keyword, that
确保我可以传递此函数的返回值 只是
ensures that I can pass the return value of this, just
就像INPUT、INT或FLOAT的返回值一样 返回到另一个函数
like the return value of input or INT or float, to another function,
比如印刷品
like print instead.
在这里 也会有很多方法来解决这个同样的问题
And here too there's going to be so many ways to solve this same problem.
我实际上可以把n的2次方
I can actually raise n to the power of 2.
我们以前没有见过这种语法 但如果您
We've not seen this syntax before, but if you
用像这样的两个星号 两颗星 把左边的东西抬起来
use two asterisks like this, two stars, that raises the thing on the left
右手边的电源
to the power on the right.
或者 原来在Python中有一个名为
Or it turns out there is in Python a function called
战俘将某事提升到某种力量
POW for raising something to the power that
接受两个参数 第一个参数是数字 第二个参数是
takes two arguments, the first of which is the number, the second of which
是指数
is the exponent.
同样 也有很多方法可以真正解决同样的问题
So there too, there's just so many ways to actually solve that same problem
也是
as well.
那么 归根结底 我们在这里做了什么？
So ultimately, what have we done here?
我们首先介绍了函数--这些动作或动词 其中许多
We first introduced functions-- these actions or verbs, many of which
将其内置到只能在您自己的代码中使用的Python中
come built into Python that you can just use in your own code.
然后我们引入了变量 您可以通过这些变量存储这些返回值
We then introduced variables via which you could store those return values
然后也许可以用它做更多的事情
and then maybe do something more with it.
在一天结束时也是如此
At the end of the day too.
您现在有能力创建、发明自己的函数
You now have the ability to create, to invent your own functions
解决像Hello这样的简单问题 或者在几周内
to solve simple problems like Hello, or in the weeks
即将到来的--更复杂、更具挑战性、更有趣的问题
to come-- much more sophisticated, more challenging, more fun problems as well.